ah
and walking
Oh
thank you
hmm
thank you verymuch
it alwaysthank you
it always helpsand I appreciate it very
muchso we've got an awesome morning
togetherthis morning and thank you for
coming so much we we have over 5,200
attendees here today we sold out within
two hours I'm sorry this is the biggest
place we can get to have this so I'm
sorry for all those people that couldn't
make it and we wish we could sell more
ticketsbut we don't know where to have
it if we do so5200 attendees over 120
sessionsover a hundred hands-on labs
where you can take your code in and get
tohelp tuning it and porting it to some
ofour newer devices and there are over
a hundred Apple engineershere this week
a thousand sorryApple engineers here
this weekto help you so there's a lot
of app of folks floating around grab
them make use of themand we hope you
havea great week here at WWDC now we're
goingto talk about three things today
you know if the if the hardware isthe
the brain and sinew of our productsthe
softwarein them is their sole and today
we are goingto talk about software we
got some greatstuff to talk about
OS10 Lion iOS 5 and some kind of
interesting new cloud stuff so let's
start with Liontell us all about Lion
I'm gonna ask to my colleagues Phil
Schillerand Craig federighi to take us
throughline and give us some demos Phil
take thefeed
oh good morning everyone how you doing
yeah come on energy in the room this is
the Developer Conference that's what I
like it I am really honored to be the
firstto present to you the first of our
new products today in this product is
allabout the Mac and the Mac is doing
incredibly wellour customer base
continues to grow at a tremendous pace
we now have over 54 million active Mac
users around theworld and growing the
customers love the products and press
and Animus have really incredible things
to say aboutit
things like thisfrom All Things D
there's really no other wayto say this
the Mac is kicking ass now that's really
nice but what did John mean well this is
what he meansthe last quarter the PC
market actually shrank year-over-year
one percent while the Mac grew 28%
and mybook that's an ass-kicking now
let's do you think this is an aberration
the Mac has outgrown the industry every
quarter forthe past five years it is
going so strong and it's because the
productsare incredible products like
the new MacBook Air it's beautifulits
thinits light its fast the whole PC
industrywants to copy it but as you
know we've been leading in notebooks for
a whilewe're the first to really drive
the majority ofour PC business to a
notebook business and it's almostthree
quarters of the Mac's we've shipped
today but whether you want a great new
notebook or a killer desktop with the
new iMacthese Macs are the best that we
have evermade in the history of Apple
andthey're great not just because of
the hardware they run but because ofthe
softwareMac os10 is the heart of the
Mac and if you'rekeeping track you know
we launched Mac OS 1010 years ago we
built it on a solidUNIX foundation we
added toit the ease-of-use and
simplicity that we know Apple is
renowned for and we built intoit
amazing technologies for all ofour
great developers to make the world's
best applications to run onit and for
thoseof you who are around and remember
this thisis what Mac OS 10 looked like
10 years ago when we launched it
it was a revolution inits day in over
thelast ten years it's evolved become
more refined morepowerful more
beautifulthan ever before the Mac os10
is looking incredibly strongso where do
we take it next well next up in OS 10 is
lying a major release with over 250 new
features and if you'dlike me to go
throughevery one of them today yes well
I'd love toI'm told I don't even have
time totell you about ten key new
featuresso we'll really get into ten
awesome features first up right into it
number one multi-touch gestures one of
the great thingsabout the mat from the
beginning was thatit uh sure Dan era of
a graphic unit user interface with a
mouseand cooking and dragging but so
much haschanged over the last 10 years
we now build multi-touch trackpads into
all of our notebooks andwe offer them
on our desktopswe've learned a lot from
iOS as well
so nowlion can count on multi-touch
from the beginning youcan have
beautiful fluidmomentum based scrolling
you canhave incredible multi-touch taps
to zoom in on stories or pictures you
can dynamically zoom with beautiful
fluid pinch motions you can swipe
throughyour photographs your slides
yourweb pages all with an incredible
physical realism that's never been
possible the PC operating system before
and this has implications across the
system anda lot of little important
areas here's a simple examplethe scroll
bar why do we have scrollbars scroll
bars were there sothey could click with
the mouse anddrag and scroll but now if
you'repushing your window with
multi-touch you don't need them they can
disappear and if a much more beautiful
reading environment but when you go to
scroll they magicallyappear give you a
senseof place and proportional size and
then disappear when youdon't need them
so multi-touch is now built throughout
the system in a very powerful way number
two
full screen applicationswe've had some
full screen applications before and
theseare really important for notebooks
11 inch and 13 inch where you want to
get take advantage of every pixel onthe
display but developers have hadto work
hardto make their applications
hand-coded to do full screen
applications including apps like like
i photo well now with line we've built
in a standardmethod for developers to
createfull screen applications and it
has a simplesystem control on the top
rightso all users know where to tap and
then bring their applications full
screen but thisis in full screen like
it was before because now you can keep
your application running full screen
with a simple swipe gestureget back to
your desktop get something you need go
back to applicationnever having left
full screen in fact you canhave more
than one full screen application running
at the same time so we'veworked on a
numberof our applications to bring them
into the new full screen mode of Lion
system applications like Safari mail
iCal iLife applicationsiPhoto iMovie
GarageBandI work with keynote numbers
and pages and all these applications
goingfullscreen to have a great
experience rightout of the box here's
anexample of how it looks this is now
runningfullscreen in Safari you can
have a beautiful place for viewing your
documentsand now there's a new feature
since we've got all this extraroom on
theleft-hand side called the reading
listkeep track of things you want to
get to later
here's iCal runningfullscreen here's
preview showing you PDF documents
runningfullscreen so you can just have
abeautiful experience like we've never
had on a computer before with full
screenapplications next feature for
manyusers this will be the best feature
of Lion it's called Mission Control now
we all like torun a lot of software the
Apple we've created many featuresto
helpcustomers find just what they need
expose for finding a document dashboard
for getting at a quick widget spaces for
organizingyour work environment but did
it all work together inone unified way
wellnow with line we've unified that
with a simplegesture to get into
Mission Controland this is a bird's-eye
view ofeverything going on in your
system on the main window well that's
the current desktopyou're working on
withall the documents now organized by
what application isrunning on them and
youcan tap on any document and bring it
to the front that'sright there Center
for you to work on up above are allyour
spaces so you can have multiple desktops
you can have multiple full screen apps
running get to any one with a single tab
on the left of those spacesas a new spa
one just for your dashboard widgets you
canget to again with a single tab
so that's Mission Control andwhat I
liketo do now is before we move on have
Craig federighi come up and give you a
demo ofthese three new features all
working togetherCraig hello good
morning so
let's take a lookat lion in action
we're going to start with gestures great
played it place to experience gestures
is here in Safarithe first thing you'll
notice is apparently something funny is
thathow simple this UI looks because
there are no scroll barsit's a really
clean look we don't need scroll bars
anymorebecause we can simply push the
content with ourfingers we can flick
and getmomentum get a nice little
bounce the page feels really alive
beneath your fingers you can also expand
your fingers and fluidly zoom justlike
thatzoom out and you get a nice little
bounce page goes right back into place
if I want to
smart zoom I just double tapwith two
fingersit's smart zooms in double tap
againsmart zooms out now I want to show
you something really cool
with gestures and that's how it can
navigate in Safari I'm going to drill
into a storyand then after I've read it
I want toactually get back to the
previous page wellnow I can just take
twofingers and swipe the page right off
to theside and return back to my
previous page
I wanna getback and swipe right back
really fantastic
in fact I can swipe throughmy entire
Safari browsing history justlike that
really smooth next upI'd like to show
youfull screen apps I'm gonna launch
iPhoto here and you can seethat I
photos adoptedlions and standard new
full screen control so I'll just take
lionor take iPhoto full screen it's a
great way to lookat my photo album if I
want toget back to my desktop take
threefingers and I can just swipe the
desktopswipe iPhoto way and back to my
desktopbut I didn't have to leave
iPhotoand take it out of full screen
it's actually right there take a peek at
itgo back just like that we love this
somuch that we made gesture is
accessible inexactly the same way swipe
over tothe left and I have access to my
dashboard you can see Safari supports
full screen as well let's gotake our
safari window full screen so now we have
our dashboard over our desktop over here
to the leftwe have Safari and of course
I photos still there in full screen as
wellyou'll notice how Safari is making
great useof all the available space on
the screen for my content but if I want
to get at my bookmarks bar my menu just
go to the topyou see they slide right
out like that really nicely and when I
wantto exit full screen I have a
control rightthere in the upper right
animates right back outlet's take a
look nowat photobooth this is an app
absolutely born to runin full screen
you can see I'm surrounded by the
curtains of the the photo boothand in
hereI can experience some fantastic new
face detectioneffects so notice as I
move thebirds actually track
it's right it's the most important
feature in line and wecan also use this
face tracking technology to perform some
targeted facial enhancements for
instanceI can finally have those big
eyes thatI've always hoped for so that
make a picture of that so that's that's
pretty cool so playing around yeah
that's great stuffso you know you can
spendhours at this so fullscreen is
fantasticbut of course Mac users love
to get do a lotof things at once and
that often meansthat they have a lot of
windows in fact my desktop often looks a
little bit morelike this right I've got
a lotgoing on so how do I get across
all of those differentactivities well I
just takethree fingers swipe up on the
trackpadand I'm in Mission Control from
here I can get at any window I want so
if I want to get itI Cal here I click
it comes forwardsweet back into Mission
Control over the dictionary same thing
and across thetop you see I have my
dashboardmy desktop my full screen apps
so I want to get to iPhoto just click
comes forwardfrom anywhere three
fingers up and I'm back in Mission
ControlI can also quick look my windows
if I just hit spacebar hereget a better
look atmy calendar or take this pile of
preview windows and spread themapart
with a little gesture up but you know
what'sreally awesome is the way that
multiple desktop spaces are now
integrated right into Mission Control
just take my mouse up to the corner of
the screen anda little space pops up I
clickI've just created a new space and
I canpopulate it by just dragging the
windows I want to workwithin that space
just like this and I've set up a new
desk
really usefulI can swipe through the
spacesof course here in admission
control go over to my desktop and if I
want tothen take even an entire app in
all of its windows and create a new
spacefor that I can click on the
previewicon drag the whole pile to the
cornerI've just created another space
and the spaces are justas easy to clean
up as they were to create I just click
they delete and theyfloat windows fly
right back to my original desktopspace
so thatis Mission Control thank you
very much
Thank You Craigjust see how these new
features now work seamlessly together to
createan incredible experience in OS 10
unlike anything we'vehad on a personal
computerbefore
next upthe Mac App Store we launched
the Mac App Store this past January and
usershave found out that it is the best
place to purchase and discover new
software applications now for years
there havebeen many software channels
to buy PC software and they all work
kindof the same way you hop in your car
you drivedown town you buy a DVD if
they happen to haveit you drive back
home you load it up or you wait for it
to comemail-order will no more well now
withthe Mac App Store you can get your
software right from the comfort of your
own homeon your Mac and in the last six
monthssomething incredible has happened
the last six months the Mac App Store
has now become the number one PC
softwarechannel for buying software
that's incredible
passing Best Buy andWalmart and Office
Depot and the developers that have
gottenon board with the Mac App Store
have seen somegreat success - for
example Autodesk they brought their
SketchBook Pro application to it and
sincethey've put it on the Mac App
Store they've seen a millionnew users
on the Mac feral interactive has brought
a hostof games including Mini Ninjas
hopefully you've allplayed it doubling
of overall revenue sincethey brought it
to the Mac App Store and small great
developers likePixelmator has brought
the amazing new image editing
application to the Mac App Storethey've
seen a quadrupling ofthe revenue in
fact they made a milliondollars in
theirfirst 20 days so the Mac App Store
has been a big hit for large and small
developers so what's newin Lion well
firstit's built right in you don't
forget it and get it and decide to use
itit's built-in for every Mac user and
there's a lotof great features for you
developers to takeadvantage of some of
them you're used to fromthe iOS App
Store like in-app purchases you cannow
build those in push notifications if you
want to alert usersabout important
informationyou can make your
applications more secure there's a
built-in sandboxing method now in the
MacApp Store and for users downloads
will be even fasterbecause you can get
theseupdates as Delta updates
so that's theMac apps on it's a really
importantpart of the whole experience
of line is you'll hear more about number
five a simple but powerful idea
launchpad would it be great if no matter
where you arein your system if you want
to getat an application and quickly
launch ityou can with a simple gesture
well now you can with launchpad you
simply makea simple gesture a pinch
motion and all your applications fly
ontoyour screen no matter where they
arein your system launchpad knows where
they areyou can have multiple pages of
applications thatyou can organize any
way you want when you go andbuy a new
application on the Mac App Store and
downloads installs rightinto your
launchpad and you can make it look
however you like you can rearrange your
icons youcan create folders just as
we're used tofrom iOS and now you can
dothat on your Mac as well so that's
launch pad next resume here's a simple
ideafrom the beginning with the
computeryou've had to run applications
sometimes you quit them you go back and
you're backat the starting point you
get you have no more windows open your
documentsaren't open you usually have
to pick a templatewhy can't a plication
x' get you back to work quickly well
that'sit resume does now when you
launch anapplication and lyan it brings
youright back to where you were when
you quitit remembers what documents you
were opened remembers the text that was
selected in the document remembers where
thepalettes were and the windows and
everything just how you like it and
resume doesn'twork just on an
applicationit works system-wide so the
next time you have to shutdown and
restart your your Mac for a reason maybe
you've installed some new software and
asked you to reboot get you like
everythingjust the way it is well don't
worry you get the new login window you
log inand lion will bring you back to
the work environmentas you left it when
you restartedall your applications
running all those spaces you set up all
just the way you like it
so that's resumed number seven autosave
from the beginning of using computers
we've all had toremember one really
important factsave save save all your
workas you're going whether it's file
save or commandS on a Mac you better
keep savingas the one time you might
forgetto save what you're doing
somethinggoes wrong and what are you
goingto hear you should have saved what
you're doing why should you whycan't
the computer help youwell that's what
lion does as you're creating a document
lion can automatically save it in the
background without you having to do
anythingwithout you having to see
anything your work is just being saved
for you this is a really powerful but
simple thing but but as we got into we
found there's more thingswe can do for
you since we're Auto saving so if you
zoomin on the title bar of your
documents you'll see the nameof your
documentis actually a menu now that you
can tap on and take advantageof the
powerof autosave but for example let's
say you're doing work and you don't like
the work youdid and you're worried it
gotauto saved over what you liked that
you've done previouslywell now I can
just select revert to last open and get
back towhere you were when you started
and maybe you love the changes you've
madeand they're exactly what you want
youdon't want it to ever get auto saved
overit again because it's perfect the
wayit is you can just select lock and
now yourdocuments locked it's like a
templateand nothing can ever change it
you can even right from within the
application so like duplicate and create
a seconddocument just like the first
one that you can start working on
anotherversion so you have the power of
all ofthis right from the title bar of
your window so that'sauto save now auto
save gave us a great idea to go even
furtherwith the next feature and that's
called versions so you're workingon a
document you'reentering the text you're
formattingyou're adding copy you're
adding graphicsand all along autosave
is saving your document in fact it's
savingall these versions of your
document as you're working so we call
that versions it's automatic youdon't
have to do anything we'll do it for you
withLion if you love something at a
split second you can of coursetake a
manual snapshot if you want and it's
very efficientwe only store the
difference betweenthe versions they're
not whole new documents
and youdon't have to worry if you ever
share your work withsomeone else that
they're goingto get all that back work
that youwon't don't want them to get
whenyou copy it off or you send it an
emailwe only send the current version
so how doyou get it take advantage of
thispower of autosave inversions
well againgo back to that menu on the
topand there's another choice there
that you may have noticed browse all
versionsyou tap on it and you get this
beautiful new interface it looks a lot
liketime machine but rather than being
about your whole system it's about that
onedocument you're working on on the
leftis the current version on the right
all the past versions you have a time
scaleon the right just like time
machineyou can scroll back through them
and they're all live you can switch to
make anyone the current one you can even
cut and paste between them so that's
versionswhat I'd like to do is ask
Craig to come back up andgive another
demoshowing how this all works together
Craig again all right well let's let's
start with launchpad you see it's an
iconright here on my dock I click I get
an instant viewof all of the
applications on my system no matter
where they're installedI can page
through themreally nicely with gestures
and when I want tolaunch let's say like
address bookit's just a single click to
bring it up can also gesture with a
forefinger pinch to get in as well
so of course when I want toadd things
to mylaunch pad the best way to do that
iswith the Mac App Store I'm going to
launch it righthere you can see on the
Mac App Store we have great featured
applicationstop paid and free apps
categories we havealso all of your
purchase tabsso then if you buy another
Mac or you buy on one Mac you wantto
get the app on the other one
youcan download them here at no
additional chargeand of course updates
with just aclick you can bring all the
apps youhave installed on your system
from the App Store
up to date well now let's try adding
Twitter to our Mac we're going to click
here and go to the Twitter product page
and with a clickyou can buy the app
actually lifts up out of theApp Store
andflies right into my Launchpad
downloads and is ready to use
from here I canjust click and position
it wherever I wantI can move it maybe
to the first page
and as you seewe have folders like this
productivity folderworks great I want
to create my own folderjust pick
something up drop it and I've created a
folderjust like that in Launchpad next
I'dlike to show you just how fantastic
the Mac is now with Lion working with
documents I'm going to open the document
that I've been working on here on the
history of guitarswhen I start editing
a documentoften I'll position my
windows just the way I like them like
this maybe open up some inspectors
position them the way I want them and
then I'll set down to editing now this
guitar this looks maybe a little bittoo
metal for my target audience all delete
that take take this move it asidemaybe
change the font hereon this on this
documentso I'm done with my edits for
now and I'm gonna quit and I want you to
watch what happens when I quit
absolutely nothing
I wasn't prompted to saveI didn't need
to be because lion was actually saving
for me all along but it wasn't just
savingmy document it was saving exactly
the state of how I was workingso now
when I go back and launch pages again
you see itbrings back all my inspectors
just the way they werebrings back my
window position where it was andeven
has my text selection highlighted just
as I left it perfect restore but we're
notjust storing the latest version of
thedocument we're keeping a history of
thedocument as it's edited so if I want
to go back maybe I regret these edits I
want to getback to the previous version
I go right here and browse all versions
and I'm taken right into the star field
where I get a view of my current version
on theleft and the history on the right
if I wantthis previous version to
becomecurrent I click restore it picks
up flies on top and becomes the current
version of my document and I'm restored
butyou saw that was actually more
history than that I'll go back into the
star field here you can see I actually
have a full timeline here on the right I
cango back to the very beginning of
this document when it was just a few
paragraphsor step forward as I was
adding pagesand so forth but when I
restorea document you know very often I
don't wantreally the holo version I
likemostly what my new document has
become but often I want to harvest maybe
just an image or perhaps a particular
slide andbring it into the current
version with versions I can because
these two windows are actually live here
so if I have on my current version maybe
a page that could really use an image to
punch it upa little bit I go back to
thispast version I see oh look there's
there's aguitar that would be just
perfectwell I can just select the
guitarand the old version copy it and
then pasteit right into the latest
version and like that I've created just
the document I was looking for and
that'sversion thanks Thank You Craig
next number9 well as long as we've had
computerswe wanted to share documents
we have a new feature to help you do
thatand make it easier than ever it's
called airdrop you've got your computer
your friends got their computer and
trying toget documents between them has
always beensuch a pain in fact the
easiest way to do this that no one's
done better than is good old sneakernet
copy it off of one walk over to your
friend's computer copy it back on
Millian solves that with a new
technologyairdrop that's a peer-to-peer
Wi-Fi based networkso how does it work
when you go intothe finder in line
you'llsee on the sources on the Left a
new choicecalled airdrop you tap it you
get a new display inside the finder what
you see isyourself Center bottom right
thereand the people around you who are
alsorunning airdrop at the same time
you see their picturesI want to drag a
document over to Shawna's computer I
justdragged the document on top of her
picture andit asked me are you sure you
want to sendthis and I confirm I do I'm
Shauna's computer because she's also now
running airdrop she sees pops up overmy
pictureI'm trying to send her a
document she confirms she wants to
receiveit and it downloads right into a
downloads folder and that's it that's
what it takes to now wirelessly share
files betweenLyon computers so it's a
peer-to-peer Wi-Fi basednetwork there's
nothing toset up its auto-discovery
Auto setup we have confirmation on both
ends just tobe safe
and your data isprotected over-the-air
because it's fully encrypted as it's
transferred so that's airdropand that
brings usto number ten number ten is
maila completely new version of mail
online it's beautiful the layout on it
is incredible
it works in a window it takesadvantage
of fullscreen you can work in a two
column or if you want to have access to
yourmail sources a three column view
right thereon the left and you see that
the design of it's really optimized
aroundreading your mail have a
beautiful full height message windowon
the left and the message listyou see
snippets like we used tofrom iOS now
builtinto mail across the top you have
a favorites barsort of like a browser
does now in mail that can be favorite
folders where you like to keepthings
you want toget at quickly probably the
most one of themost powerful features
is searching withsearching now we have
new search suggestionsso you start to
type what you'relooking for and mail
recognizeswhether that's a person or a
subjectand prompts you with the choices
you haveacross your entire mail
databasewhat you can find quickly when
you selectone it becomes what we call a
search token that'san interactive
search token where you can set some
parameterson it and you can have more
than one and create boolean searches if
you wantbut probably the best feature
of the new mail is something we callyes
youcan love that it's okay boolean
searches
probably the best feature somethingwe
call conversationview in male today as
you've got a conversationgoing you've
gotsome messages you've responded to or
replied andforwards you see the mail
gets longerand longer and they're
indentedand color coded things stripped
outit gets more and more difficult to
follow the flow of this and appreciate
the messagesthat were sent well now in
line there's abrand-new conversation
view that shows your messagesjust as
they weresent you see the messages you
see thepeople who send them you see the
attachments still in line all there for
youto view it it's completely
compatible with doing email with other
people whodon't have line and can't get
the same beautiful view so that's male
and lion I'd like to bring Craig up for
onelast demo to show off male ok well I
absolutelylove the new male in lion
let's let's take a lookso it's got this
greatfull height message list perfect
for laptopsjust like this I've got my
message list on the side with snippets
makes it really easyto find the message
I'm looking forwith this new favorites
bar across thetop so I can click
through mymailboxes really easily but
if I want to get back to my full list
they're available right here as well I
really find the new search to be just
awesomebecause when I search I'm often
searching for a person let's say like
PhilI start typing pH see it prompts me
forpeople in my mail right now that
match so I go Phil Schillerfound
messages from Phil just like thatI can
useit can retarget the search to
specificinboxes or search all and of
courseas Phil showed you I can pick
whether I'm searching forfrom two or
the entiremessage
wellsuggestions don't just apply to
searching for peoplethey also work for
other things as well like let's say a
subject I'll search forTripp you see
that it's actually prompting me do you
wantto search for messages that contain
Tripp or where Tripp justappears in the
subjectline or even suggest specific
subject lines that matchso I can select
thisand I've done a subject search on
Trippwhat about dates I'm going to type
March start typing March there you see
it promptsme March 2011
like thatI've searched for all my
messages in March but what's really
awesome is the way you can combine these
reallyquickly to pinpoint just the
search you're looking for solet's say
lookingfor a message about that Phil
sent me it's the subjectwas something
about reservationit was from Phil
Schillerand it was last month like that
drills down to exactly the message we're
looking for it's really nice
as awesome as thatis my favorite
feature is conversationsit's this
beautifulview of all the messages that
were sent in the conversation just as
they were sentwith all the images and
so forth and you'll notice that all of
that extra forwarded reply text that's
redundantin the conversation is
strippedright out it's gone but if I
wantto show it I want to see mail the
way it kind of looks inlessor mail
programsI can click like this it folds
rightout yeah this is awesome if I want
to replyto a particular message in a
conversation I can hover we get a reply
control and watchthis animation loop so
message hopsright out so that's great
andfinally when you want to file a
wholeconversation away you can just
drag it all at once
drag all the messages put it your folder
and you're done that's mail in line
thank you
so those are thetop ten features of
mail and there's so much use we have
lion and there is so much more for you
tolearn about and discover and lion
amazing features just to bring up a few
and don't windows users who wantto
upgradeto a Mac deserve a migration
feature justlike we Mac users have well
now thereis in line when you upgrade
fromWindows we can help you migrate and
get to abetter computing experience
there's File Vault- yeah so for all of
you who want more security and
encryption on your hard drive you have
that facetimes built in even servers all
new with Lionserver isn't another
operatingsystem it's just a bunch of
applications you can purchase to run on
top ofLion so amazing depth of features
foryou and for all the developers out
herewe have over 3,000 new API so you
to take advantage of the power of Lion
amazing stuff you can do all the things
we showed here you can have full screen
applications you can create versionsyou
cantake advantage of autosave all of
that can easily be done with all these
newAPI s so line is an incredible new
new release so how are wegoing to get
it well inthe past one thing every
versionof Mac OS 10 is shared in common
isit came on an optical disk no more
now line we available only in the Mac
App Store
and that allows usto make it the
easiest upgrade you have ever seen when
it's ready you'll go intothe Mac App
Store and you'll see a page there where
you can readabout it see screenshots
read reviews when you're ready clickbuy
and it downloads right onto your Mac and
starts the upgradeprocess right there
so it's on the Mac App Store to be about
4 gigabytes in size about the same size
as a single HD movie that you might
downloadit installs right in place no
more rebooting from anoptical disk and
because it's partof the Mac apps from
the Mac App Store rules it follows the
same rules when you purchase ityou can
useit on all of your personal
authorized Mac's you have to buy
multiplecopies that's lying
I know what you're thinking whatshould
we chargefor this but what would you
charge in the past most major leases of
Mac OS10 have been one hundred and
twenty nine dollars and I think there's
a lot herefor $129 but we love it so
much that we want to make it available
toeven more people so we're going to
price it at just $29.99
I was hoping you'regonna like that so
when doyou all get your hands on it
here at theconference we're gonna have
a Developer Previewthe latest developer
preview available today for you to
downloadand take advantage of
everything you've seen up here and for
customersone will be available in July
so very very soon coming in July so that
islion that's the first four new
products we wanted to tell you about
today the nextproduct we're going to
talk aboutis iOS 5 and to do that I'd
liketo invite up Scott Forstall
welcome so I'm here to tellyou about
iOSfive before I get into the cool
stuff let me give you a quick update on
iOSas you know iOS powers the iPhone
theiPad and the iPod Touch and to date
we have soldwait for it over two
hundred million iOS devices
and that makes iOS the number one mobile
operating system with more than 44
percent at forty four percent of the
market now the latestaddition to the
iOS family is the iPad 2which is an
incredible producteven thinner and
lighterthan the original it comes in
black andwhite that has cameras on the
front and back it is an amazing product
and our customers just couldn't wait to
get their handson it or else they'd
actually did have to wait to get their
hands on it
in the firstfourteen months we have
already sold more than 25 million iPads
we createda whole new category of
device with the iPad and have sold more
than 25 million with the iPad to joins
theiPhone and the iPod Touch for an
incredible lineupof iOS devices we've
got some great stores to go alongwith
these as well
I like the iTunesmusic store we've
already soldmore than 15 billion songs
fromthe iTunes music store this course
makes it the number oneretailer of
music in the world
next is the iBook storeyou know we
launched the iBook store justa little
more than a yearago already all six
major publishers have signed upand are
providingbooks to the bookstore our
customers loveit
our customers have downloaded more than
130 million books great and of course
there's theApp Store now the size and
momentum of the App Store is really hard
to fathom there are currently more than
425 thousand apps on the App Store and
more than90 thousand of these were made
specifically forthe iPad it takes full
advantage of the large touchscreen
display and they make the iPad a better
productso we'd like to thank our
developers for these great apps
now ourcustomers love it our customers
havedownloaded more than 14 billion
apps from theApp Store and that's in
lessthan three years it's amazing
now our developers are being well
rewardedfor this apples so far has paid
out more than two and a half billion
dollarsto developers building apps for
the App Store thank you
now theseapps as you know cover every
genre imaginablethere's great travel
apps like this walking tour from Lonely
Planet they're incredibly addictive
games I'd say evenmind controlling the
addictive games like tiny wingsgreat
entertainment titles like HBO GO which
lets you takeHBO wherever you are and
you can watch it right on your iPad
they're deep apps like mobile mem which
allow physicians tolook at CT scans and
PET scansright on their iPad and this
has been fda-approved this next one from
Jepsen's been FAA approvedand it allows
pilots to look at the charts andthe
mapsfor airports around the world right
on their iPad and there's great business
apps outthere like WebEx which allows
you tohave a multi-party video
conferenceand really hold a virtual
meeting so some great apps outthere for
our stores we have more than 225 million
accountsall with credit cards and
one-click purchasing to make it really
easyfor our customers to find what they
wantpurchase it and download it
directly to their device these stores go
with an incredible lineupof iOS devices
let's talk about thefuture of iOS and
that is iOS 5
iOS 5 is a major releasethis is
incrediblefor our developers and for
our customers
for developers there are more than 1500
new api's and some great enhancementsto
our toolsfor our for our users there
morethan 200 new features let me go
aheadand walk you through ten now
number one notifications
I'm sure you'reall familiar with
notifications we look something like
thisit looks best when giants are on
top soyou get scoring alerts you have
alerts to pop up theyget into audio
they can also badgethe home screen
icons well these have been massively
popular in fact we have alreadypushed
more than ahundred billion push
notificationsis scaled beautifully
we've heardfrom our customers that are
receivingso money they'd like a better
UI to get them and we agree and so we
have builtsomething that solves some of
theproblems in the current one
currently when you get a notificationit
interrupts you if you're playing a game
you get a modal alert you have to deal
with that mode alert before you can go
onalso in the lock screen you get this
nice list ofthings that have happened
while your phone's been locked but when
you unlock itthat list isn't persistent
there's no way to get back to that list
and go through those notifications well
we have designed a solution thatsolves
those issuesand goes far beyond it and
we call it notification center
Notification Center is a single place
which combines together all of your
notifications you can get to it at any
time from anywhere on your iPhone or
iPad oriPod touch just by swiping your
finger downfrom the top to reveal the
Notification Center
so we thinkit is beautiful it has your
missed callsand voicemails text
messages mail messages scoringalerts
Facebook updatesany push notifications
thatcome from the App Store all end up
righthere in Notification Center and
we've evenadded stocks and weather
right up topnow we didn't stop there
notifications are no longer interrupting
so now if you're playing a game and
someonesends you say a text message a
nice animationfrom the top it's right
thereyou can keep on playing your game
andit'll automatically dismiss itself
you could have just tapped on it who
take you to that app but doesn't matter
becauseyou can always get back to it
any time just by swiping your finger
downfrom the top we've also improved
thelock screen you can see more
information for notifications here and
oneof my favorite features is for any
one of the notifications in the lock
screenyou can just slide your finger
acrossit and it takes you directly to
the app that sent the notification let
me go aheadand just show this to you
now so I've got a phone here runningiOS
5you see more information there now I'm
just going to swipe my finger right
across that text message and it takes me
directly tothe messages app and right
into the conversation it's really
convenientnow to get to the
Notification Center just swipe my finger
down from the top and there it is
dismiss it by swiping up really nice
animationyou can see that we're still
in winter here in San Francisco I get
allof my messages here so text messages
and scoring alertsdown at the bottom
here I have some alerts from mlb.com at
batif I tap on that X button I can just
go aheadand clear that out if I see
another notification like the Facebook
oneI tap on it takes me directly to the
Facebook app so it's really convenient
and at any time again swipe down from
the top andyou get
back toNotification Center and that is
Notification Center
number two is newsstandyou know I love
reading newspapersand magazines right
on my iphone my iPad and recently we
added subscriptionsthis makes it easier
for you get all the new issues without
missing anythingalready
most of the major publishersof
magazinesand many of newspapers have
signed up tosupport subscriptions these
are incredible titlesthings like
NationalGeographic and spin to great
music magazines and of course when you
read these on your iPad you getaudio
and video in addition to all the
articles Vanity Fair science magazines
like Popular Mechanics andpopular
science Esquire GQ fashion magazines
like ElleThe Oprah Magazine tech
magazines like Wired and automobile
magazines and sports magazinesThe New
Yorker and newspapers new ones like the
daily butalso the New York Times the
SanFrancisco Chronicle Daily Telegraph
andother international papers and we've
now created a single place rightin the
app store thatcombines all of these
newspaper and magazinesso you can find
themall in one place when you purchase
them they're automatically downloaded
and placed in the newsstandit's a new
place right onthe home screen looks
like it's beautifulnews rack in
addition to this we do background
downloads
so if a newissue comes out say of a
newspaperwhile you're sleeping when you
wake upand pick up your iPad that new
newspaperis already there ready for you
to read it and you can read it offline
on topof this we set the cover to be
the front page of the new newspaperand
we'll set it to be the cover of the new
magazine for magazines
so that is newsstand next is Twitter now
as I'm sureeveryone's familiar Twitter
is an incredibly popular service people
send more thana billion tweets per week
andwe hear from a lot of our customers
on iPhoneand iPad and iPod touch that
they love Twitterand so we want to make
it eveneasier for all of our customers
to use Twitter on iOS products we're
doing a numberof things for this first
we're addingsingle sign-on so now when
you goto the Settings app its built in
on the iPhone or iPad you can enter your
username and password and now you're
configured for Twitter for any app you
download off the App Store it'll just
say can Iuse your credentials when you
say yes you're logged in you don'tneed
to relogin every single time so single
sign-on
next we've integrated Twitter in with
manyof our apps like camera and photos
so now if you're at a concert you take a
photoand you want to tweet that photo
just tap on the action button it's a new
option tweetand it brings up this
beautiful tweet sheet gives you a nice
thumbnail of the photo give you a
countdown ofhow many characters you
have left to type and youcan even
optionally add your locationtap on that
and then you've tweeted the photo it's
that simple in addition to tweetingfrom
photos and camera you can tweet articles
from Safari websites you can tweet
videos from YouTube and youcan tweet
about businesses or locations for maps
beyond all of this we added integration
with contacts now you might havea lot
of contacts that don't have photos but
Twitter may have photos for those people
and soyou can use Twitter to
automaticallyupdate the photos in your
contact list and even the at user name
for your friendsand that's Twitter
integration throughout the OS
next isSafari
you knowSafari is the best mobile web
browser outthere it's also the most
popular in fact nearly two-thirds of all
mobileweb browsing is done on Safari
beyond this we took apples Safari engine
and open sourced it and it's the basis
of all web browsing onAndroid so Safari
engine is the basisof more than 90% of
all webbrowsing on mobile devices well
iOS5 we're making Safari even better
we've got some great features the first
isreader Safari reader becomes
available up here as a new button when
you're reading a storyon a website if
youjust tap on that button we take the
story you're reading and make it front
andcenter we get rid of all the
distractions set the font size rights
and even if it's amulti-page story so
you'd haveto tap through multiple web
pages normally to get to itwe put in a
singlescrolling story it's really
convenient
on topof that you can out email the
contents ofthe story before you can
just email the link but now when you
email youget the link plus the contents
in your compose window and all and all
of this works really well on the iPad it
worksgreat on the iPhone as well it's a
perfect sizefor it sets the font size
right it's really nice to read stories
so that's the Faro reader the second one
is readinglists reading lists is a
simple and convenientway for you to
quickly save a story to read it later
just put it in the reading list and when
you add an item toreading list it gets
addedto the reading list on all of your
iOSdevices and even the reading list on
Safari on Macand Safari on Windows
so if you don't have timeto finish it
here on the iPad you can finish reading
it lateron your iPhone and the next
feature istabbed browsing we have added
fulltab browsing and Safari on the iPad
and you know letme just show it to you
alright so here I have iPad running iOS
5 I'll launchSafari here and the first
thing you'llsee with tab browsing is it
is lightningfast to switch between
Windows now just tap onit and you're
there great now I'mon the DP review
site which is a fantasticreview site
for camerasand they have really
extensive reviews in fact youdon't have
to tap through many manypages to read
the whole review but I like this one
here it's a 20 pages long well if I tap
the readerbutton here it loads the
entire story up andreader now I can
just scroll through it gets rid of all
thedistractions lets me concentrate
justin the content that is reader
you even see thatwhen it goes between
pages here where you would have had to
you know tap to say next page it
automaticallygives you a little page
breakso you know when it's going
throughthose pages now let's say if I
don't have time to finish the story
right now I can just tap the bookmarks
bar item and here I have reading list I
tap plus and now it's added this to my
reading list and again I can go finish
this onMac on you know on Safari on my
Mac orany of my other iOS devices it's
greatand if I really like this and I
want totweet about it let me show you
the Twitter integrationwhile we're here
by tap tweet brings up the tweet sheet
we do completionsof a hit I have a
friend Garydone so I hit at G
automatically fills in the nametap that
and say you know I like this one and I
canoptionally add my location tap send
andit's tweeted it's that easy so some
really great Safari enhancements and
Twitter integration throughout
all right next up these are reminders
youknow all of us are constantly
creating lists of things list of things
todo list of things to buy like a
grocery listsome of them have a place
associated likedon't forget to walk the
dog when I get homeand some have a time
associated say buy concert tickets
Monday at 10:00 a.m. so that's when they
go on salewouldn't be great if you get
rid of all these scraps of paper and
storeall this on your phone but beyond
that if your phoneactually reminded you
to do things as opposed to just
statically keeping a list of things well
that's exactlywhat the reminders app
does on the reminders app youcan store
listsof things multiple lists of things
for a trip to San Francisco or birthday
party or a grocerylist you can store
dates associated with these reminders so
you'll be remindedon that date you can
also sign location this isreally cool I
could set upa reminder to say remind me
to call my wife when I leave the
conventiontoday and it'll set a
geofence
up aroundMoscone Center and so when I
getin my car to leave it will pop up
and takeall
it solves theproblem of unliving right
now I promisecall on the car you can of
course search throughall your reminders
and reminders will syncwith iCal on the
Mac usingCalDAV and even without look
on Windows usingexchange and that is
reminders
next is camerayou know the iPhone 4 is
widelyregarded as having one of the
best cameras on a mobile phone it's also
one of the most popular in factif you
look at cameras used to take photos and
then post them toFlickr now this is all
cameras not just cameras on phonesyou
see where the iPhone 4 is it is already
by far the most popular camera on a
phone to take photos and it very soon
will bethe most popular camera overall
we want to make using the camera even
betterand that's what we're doing the
firstthing we're doing is making it way
faster just get in and takea photo
so now ifthere's some moment happening
your kids doing something really cute
youwant to capture it you double click
that home button you get a new camera
iconwhen you tap on that camera icon
you're brought directly and immediately
to the camera and you're ready to take a
photonow what's really cool about this
iseven if you have a passcode set we'll
take you rightinto take a new photo
we'll protect it and you can't see any
previous photos you'vetaken or anything
elsein the phone without typing your
passcode being start taking a passcodea
picture immediatelyand you can even use
thevolume up button now to click
that sound I think people say use the
shutter buttonto turn your volume up so
in additionto this we've added optional
gridlinesso you can use the rule of
thirds to compose your photo or line it
up you can now pinch to zoom right
within the cameraand if you hold your
finger over part of the scene now we'll
set the auto exposureand auto focus
lockyou can even move it around you
know stick to that
now this is a reallyadvanced feature
when we broughtit to the iPhone and
we've made it really easy for everyone
to use
now nextonce you've taken your great
photosyou can now edit them right on
your iPhone and your iPad you do things
like crop and rotate redeye reductionso
if you'vetaken the photo at left where
the flash has caused aredeye you can
automatically remove that redeye
righton your iPhone or iPad and we even
brought over theone-click enhance that
we pioneeredin iPhoto on the Mac and it
broughtthat to iOS so you can see when
you applied one tapenhance to the right
how the color tones look so much nicer
how it pulls detail out of shadow it's
really niceso some great photo editing
features and reallynice camera
enhancements
next ismale now male is one of the most
used applicationson both the iPhone
iPod andiPod Touch iPad and iPod Touch
and we're making it even better in iOS 5
we're adding rich text formatting so you
can set thingsas bold italic and
underline you can control the
indentation so you're forwarding
something you can uh ninten it's or
further indent it you can now dragthe
addresses betweentwo CC and BCC don't
have to retypethem again we've added
support for flagging so you can flag and
unplug this next one has been a
incredibly popular requestin addition
to searchingfrom two and subject you
can searchthe entire contents of all
your messagesboth the messages on your
phone and all the messages back on the
mailserver so search the entire
contents ofyour messages for the iPad
we added areally nice swipe to inbox
gesture so it makes it really nice to
use this in portrait so you swipe it on
tap on something swipe it off and with
every release ofIowa spot or is we
continueto add more support for our
enterprisecustomers and one example of
that in iOS 5 is we added support for
s/mime so now I think we've done a
reallynice job of this now if you have
the certificateof someone else you
automatically get this lock icon right
in the addressing field just to show you
this willbe encrypted
when sent to the other person let me
just go ahead and give you a demo of few
ofthese features now alright so first I
can show you a simple gesture I just
pull on theinbox right from there so
anywhereyou are when your porch adjust
pull iton you have to go hunt up and
find the rightbutton for it you can see
we're flagging here so I can tap on that
flagged messagea one other feature
we've added is a builtin dictionary
throughout the OS as a service now so
before we had a dictionary inthe iBooks
app but wenow brought that
to the entire OS so all apps from the
App Store can use it so here if I press
downlets and lychees I don't know what
thatis let's say I get a define in
addition to copy tap define there it is
built-in dictionary it's great if I say
respond to thismessage again I can grab
oneof these addresses now just drag it
to BCC dragged itto and rearrange it
it'sreally nice and easy as one more
feature I want to showyou it's actually
a system-wide feature having to do with
the keyboardwhen we released the
original iPhone we revolutionized the
way people would tight onmulti-touch
displays and we keep on challenging
ourselvesto make that even better we
have a new variantof the keyboard in
iOS 5 for theiPad which we think people
who like to type with their thumbs while
holding it are reallygoing to like in
thebottom right you see the keyboard
button and now has some grab handlesif
I justtake those and drag it up it
splits itinto two
so what it does is it moves the keys
closer to your thumbs on theside so you
can you can put it wherever you want
it's really nice and it's persistent for
every app in the systemit just stays
whereyou put it
we want to put it back downjust press
andhold to dock and merge it goes back
down to the bottom so even a split
keyboard
that'smail number eight PC free
so we built these incredible devicesthe
iPhonethe iPad and people get them home
they openup their box and I see this I
say well what now we're living in a post
PC world in fact especially with the
iPad we're offering in the post PC world
we have a lotof customers coming to us
andsaying I want to buy an iPad as my
only device I don't know in a computer I
wantto buy an iPhone is my only device
my only actuallyinternet access for
where I livewill be my iPhone
we know we're selling into a lotof
places where the households just don't
have computersand they want to buy an
iOSdevices their only device and that's
exactlywhat we're going to support an
iOS 5now you take your iPhone out of
the box insteadof seeing this you're
goingto see this
you can now set up and activate your
device right on the device and you are
readyto go it's that easy and of course
there's someother things we had to do
tomake this possible software updates
are now over-the-air
so you no longerneed to go and plug
into acomputer just to update your
software and of course they're now Delta
updates so instead ofdownloading the
entire OS you just download what's
changednow the next thing we did is we
we looked at all ofthe apps in the
iPhone iPad iPod touch and asked
ourselves what are thereasons that
people go back to a computer today and
let's add that functionalityright to
iOSso for instance you have to go back
to a computerto create calendars or
delete calendarsyou can now create and
delete calendarsright from iOS you saw
for photos we've added really
significant editing functionality in
there so you cancrop rotate one tap
enhance redeye reductionright from
withinyour iOS device even in mail now
you can create mailboxes and delete
mailboxes right fromiOS so we looked at
all ofthe apps in the i phone and the
ipad added that functionality so now if
youwant to cut the cord you can
next is gamecenteriOS is the most
popular gamingplatform on the planet
there are more than a hundred thousand
game and entertainment titlesin the App
Storeand so about nine months ago we
launched Game Center and we did it to
make it even easier for people to find
playersto play games against and also
to makeit easy for you to compare how
you're doingagainst your friends well
in justnine months we have 50 million
Game Center users now to put that into
perspectiveXbox Live has been around
forabout eight years and they have
around 30 millionusers so Game Center
is verypopular and we're making it even
better in iOS 5 to make it more fun and
social we're addingphotos you can see
photos of your friends change your
photos you cannow compare yourself
against yourfriends using achievement
pointsper game you can see friends of
friendsas well you also will get
recommendedfriends that might be great
people to place on the games that you
like
we've also added gamerecommendations so
there might be somereally great games
outthere maybe they're new that you
don't knowabout and we'll help you
discover those once you'vediscovered a
game you likeyou can purchase and
downloadit directly from Game Center
now this is great both for our customers
andfor our developers another thing
we've done forour developers is we've
added supportfor turn-based games right
in to the OS
there are some great turn-based games
out therelike Scrabble but the
developer had to do all thework for
that and now that's supported right out
ofthe box in iOS 5 so some really nice
enhancements toGame Center
next is iMessage nowI believe we have
the best messaging client out there on
the iPhoneit works tremendously well to
send textmessages and photos and videos
and our customerslove it our iPhone
customers but whatabout our iPad
customers and our iPodTouch customers
they've been asking us fora messaging
solutionand so in iOS 5 we're launching
a new messaging service betweenall iOS
5 customers
and we call it iMessage soI message
supports the iPhonethe iPad and the
iPod touch it does everything you've
come to expectfrom our messaging app on
the iPhoneso you can send text messages
photos videos send contacts do group
messaging everything you come to expect
and we've added some really nice new
features things like delivery receipts
so you can see if it's been delivered to
the other person's device optional read
receiptsso you can see if it's been
read this is why myfavorite typing
indication so you can tell now if
someone starts typing and they're
responding toyou you know you're about
to get that message I messages are
pushed to all your devicesso if you
start a conversation onyour iPad and
later pick up youriPhone you can pick
up right where you left off with all the
context of thatconversation to date is
supported over both 3G and Wi-Fiand
everything is sent encryptedover the
where over there over the air and I like
to just giveyou a demo of iMessage now
to do so I also like toinvite up jaws
vice president of product marketing to
helpme hey does Scott thanks for having
meabsolutely you don't mind I'm a play
game though uhplaying again okay try
not to bother me right here frolic
marketing uh he's on the iPhone on the
Left I'm on my iPad on the right hand
side I go ahead and launch messages here
so here I havea conversation go with
Charles normally we don't stand next to
eachother we have these conversations
so most I've talked to you all week
let's grab lunch after the show I know
okay so when I send this to them you'll
notice ashe plays the game it comes in
right at the top and you can keep on
playing thegame so it's not
interrupting him as does his lovely job
playingI'm on a roll don't bother me
butat any time he can get right back to
that message
Oh at anytime I think this might be good
timeha ha that's so a dick just by
pullingdowntown that takes him right to
thisnow as he starts typing see on my
side where there's the three dots of the
balloon that lets me knowhe's currently
responding well check maybe some other
messageswhile he's doing so so then
when he sendsthe message you see where
it's cents he gets a little delivered it
already knows it's been deliveredright
to my device and when I tap on his
message it sends a read receipt saying
rad 11:15 a.m. he knows I've read it so
readreceipts three
we can also sendhigh-quality photos and
videos let mego ahead and choose a
photo herealright maybe we have a
picnic by the bridgeoh that's so sweet
send it a littlepicture again you can
tell from the dotsand his side that I'm
composing it right now send it off and
again we go over Wi-Fi as well as 3G
sends it overagain it gets it nice high
quality and the entire transmission is
encryptedover-the-air and again I'm on
my iPad so it supports iPad iPod Touch
andiPhone thanks jealous
can't wait forlunch
soI message and we're actually building
this on the push notification system
we've built so we know how to scale this
we have incredible features herein iOS
5notification system which is just a
reallynice newsstand makes it even
better to read your newspapers and
magazinesright on your iPad or iPhone
great Twitter integration a new
reminders app you can bePC free if you
want and the new iMessage application
and these arejust 10 of the more than
200 new user features there's really
something for everyone in iOS 5 there's
other thingslike airplay mirroring you
can now mirror your entire iPadto write
to your televisionwirelessly using
Apple TV
Wi-Fisync to iTunes before you had
exactly beforebefore you had to go back
and plug into your computer to sync and
now whenyou are charging at night let's
say your iOS device will automatically
findiTunes over Wi-Fi and sync with it
and beforeit sinks it'll back itself up
so you automaticallyget backed up every
singleday there's also some really nice
newmultitasking gestures so you can
just flick right between your apps it's
really nice we're not only is there's
something for every one of our customers
there's something for every one of our
developers some great new development
tools including significant enhancements
toxcode instruments in the simulator
even core imagewe brought over the
powerful core imageframe works with Mac
OS10 - iOS this allows developers to do
complex imageoperations like redeye
reduction face detectionright from
within their apps so you're asking
yourself when are you getting it and the
answer is we're giving a developer seed
to you today
this is gonna begreat for the
conference as you learn aboutall the
newapi's than all the sessions this
week you can go and use those api's
immediately using your seed and iOS5
will ship to allof our customers this
fall
iOS 5 will support the same devicesthat
we supported with our last software
update so that's the iPhone 3GS and
iPhone4 all the iPads iPad and iPad 2
and the third and fourth generation iPod
Touch and that is iOS 5
and that is the second ofthe software
products we wantto tell you about today
to tell you aboutthe third I like to
turn it backover to Steve
so you like everything so far well I'll
trynot to blow it so I get to talk
about iCloudwe've been working on this
for sometime now and we're really
excitedabout it about ten years ago we
had one of our most important insights
and that was that the PC was going to
become the digital hub foryour digital
life what does that mean well it meant
thatthat's where you were going to put
your digital photos where else wereyou
going toput them your digital video off
your digital camcorder and of course
your music right you were going to
acquire it in the device or potentially
on your Mac and you were going to
basically sync it tothe Mac and
everything was goingto work fine and it
didfor the better part of 10 years but
it's broken down in the last few years
why well because the devices have
changedthey now all have music they now
all have photos they now all have video
and so if I acquire a song I buy it
righton my iPhone I want to get that to
my other devicesright I pick up my iPad
it doesn't havethat song on it so I
have tosync my iphone to my Mac then I
have to sync myother devices to the Mac
to getthat song but then they've
deposited some photoson the Mac so I
have to sync the iPhone again with the
Mac to get thosephotos and keeping
these devices in syncis driving us
crazy
so we've got a great solutionfor this
problem and we think this solution is
our nextbig insight which is we're
going to demote the PC in theMac to
just be a device justlike an iPhone an
iPador an iPod touch and we're going to
move the digital hub the center of your
digitallife into the cloud because all
these new devices have communications
built into them they can all talk to the
cloud whenever they wantand so now if I
getsomething on my iPhone it sends up
to the cloud immediatelylet's say I
take some pictureswith it
those pictures are inthe cloud and they
are nowpushed down to my devices
completely automatically and now
everything isin sync with me not even
having to think about it I don't even
have to take thedevices out of my
pocketI don't have to be near my Mac or
PCnow some people think the cloud is
just a hard disk in the sky right and
you take a bunchof stuff and you put it
in yourDropbox or your I disk or
whatever and it transfers it up to the
cloudand stores and then you drag
whateveryou want back out on your other
devices we think it's way morethan that
and we call it iCloud now iCloud stores
your content inthe cloud and wirelessly
pushes it to all yourdevices so it
automatically uploadsit stores it and
automatically pushesit to all your
other devices but also it's completely
integrated with your apps and so
everythinghappens automatically and
there's nothing new tolearn it just all
works
it just works
now you might askwhy should I believe
them they're the ones thatbrought me
mobile me it wasn't our finest hour let
mejust say that but we learned a lot
nowthe three core apps in Mobile me or
contacts calendar and mail three things
we'd obviouslylike kept up to date
we've thrown them away we've reacted and
rewritten them from the ground up to be
iCloud apps and we've put them on all of
ourdevices so as an example in contacts
when I make anew contact on my iPhone
it's automatically brought up to the
cloud where it's storedon the cloud
right the truth is on the cloud and then
it's automatically pushed downto my
other devicesso they're all in sync
it's that easy
I just update a contacton my iPhone and
don't eventhink about it and that
contact is updated on all my other
devices and if I change it on any device
it's updated on all devices wirelessly
automatically withoutme doing a thing
so that's contacts here's calendars
works much thesame way I make a new
calendar event on my iPhone it's stored
inthe cloud and it's pushed to my other
devices pretty cool
we've also added calendar sharing so as
an example ifI'm sharing a few
calendars with my wife school andsoccer
calendars let's say right and I add a
newcalendar for a teacher parent
conference on my phone it's again
automatically pushed up tothe cloud and
automaticallypush to my wife's iPhone
if she adds
the key adds an appointment fora soccer
game againgoes up to the cloud and back
to my iPhoneit's that simple
and so calendars has it stores your
calendars in the cloudchanges on any
deviceor push to all your devices and
we have shared calendarsand we think
you're goingto love the new calendars
it just works
and then we have mail mailis in the
bestshape of all but it's even better
nowwe give you a mail accountant at me
calm your new messages againour push to
all your devicesand like will use
through your inboxand folders are all
kept up to dateon all devices
so that's mail and no ads
we build productsthat we want for
ourselvestoo and we just don't want to
ads so wecan't get there so these are
the three appsthat form the core of
mobile me we used to sell them for a
subscription price of $99 annually as of
today this product ceases to existand
thosethree apps are
but we didn't stop therewe've got three
more apps that we've broughtinto the
iCloud universe the first is of course
the App Store the App Store you've
bought a lotof apps so far and you can
buy them of coursedirectly on your
devices
maybe the app youwant isn't on the
device you've got with youso for all
your purchase historynow
you can see it onall your devices even
if the apps not there and we've added
this button here which is download from
the cloudand if you want that app on
that device you just push that button
and that app is automatically sent to
that device right and there's no extra
charge
no extra charge now we've done that for
your purchase history what about four
devices you buy in the future well four
deviceswhen you buy them in the future
you want to buy Yelp let's say the cloud
downloads it to all your devicesagain
at no extra chargeall automatically
so that's what we'redoing with the App
Store iBooks same thing you've got your
purchase historyof all the books you
bought on any device you want to get it
on your iPhone se just push the button
it downloads to that device when you buy
a new iBooklet's say you want to buy
this book here thewave it downloads it
to all yourdevices now and if you're
readingit on one device let's say
you're readingit on your iPad and
you've just got to run you get to a page
youbookmark that page that bookmark is
sentup to the cloud and stored and
again push to all yourother devices so
maybe you can read anotherthe rest of
the chapter as an exampleon the train
towork it all just works
and now back up we talked about beingPC
freeScott talked about how you can
wirelesslybackup your devices daily to
your PC or yourMac but let's do it to
the cloud as well for thosepeople that
want to be completely PC free so we've
addedwireless backup to the cloud and
basicallyonce daily we're going to
backup a lot of your important contents
to the cloud if you ever get a new phone
and have to replace a phone you
literally type in your Apple ID and
password and everything will be loaded
onto that phone automatically and wires
so we automatically do daily backups to
iCloud over Wi-Fi
webackup your purchase music apps and
books we backup your camera roll with
your photos and videos we backup your
device settingsand we backup your app
data all to the cloud so that isbackup
and those are three other apps that come
with iCloud but we couldn't stop there
and so we have a final three apps that
areamazing the most inventive part of
iCloudI think and I'd love to tell you
about the first one is documents in the
cloud so if I'm on my iPad and I create
a page as documentsright I create a
Pages documentand it automatically
uploadsit and stores it in the cloud
when I close that document completely
automaticallyand it then pushes it to
all the devicesthat I have pages on so
I can get the document between my
devices and we have put that into Pages
Numbers and Keynoteas a matter of fact
the versions wejust released last week
have this in there and to demonstrate
what this is like with I work I'd love
to invite Roger Rosner who's our VP of I
work up to giveus a quick demo
thank you Steve
all right let's take a look at how I
work andiCloud will work together let's
say you'reworking on a keynote
presentationon your iPad making a
beautiful presentation with all those
awesome keynote graphic effects and
animations but you're awayfrom home you
didn'tbring your iPad with you and you
runinto somebody who wants to see your
presentationwell the good news is last
week we shipped I work for iPhone and
evenbetter for anybody who bought and
iWork app for your iPad you can download
that app for your iPhone at no
additional chargeso let's fire up
keynote onthis phone this is the first
time we've run ithere so it's going to
say hithen it's going to say do you
want to use iCloud we say yes and
immediatelyit sees all your keynote
presentations you've been working onin
the cloud and starts to download them in
thebackground to your iPhone so I'll
openthis one we were just looking at
and as you cansee it's all there
it even remembered what slide we were
looking at and if I wantto I can just
hit play play it right on my iPhone and
I'd put exactly zero effort into getting
thatfile over here pretty
of course all the iWork appsuse iCloud
so let's take a look at pagesand you
know what imagine you're out and you
you're inspiredto make some changes to
a document you've been working on so I'm
going to move this graphic over here
maybe Ijust took a photograph that I
thinkwould be great to spruce up my
cover page so I'll go tomy camera roll
I'd serve my graphic
here's alignment guides to place it and
I'm doneand I stick the phone in my
pocket and I forget about it and in the
backgroundiCloud is grabbing all those
changes and then immediately pushing
them backdown to my iPad so when I get
home
pick up theiPad fire up pages you can
see in the upper left my document
thumbnailsalready been updated
and there are all my editsabsolutely no
effort on my part and that is how I work
works with iCloudI think you're going
to like it
thank you thanks Roger
and documents in the cloud really
completesour iOS document storage story
- in other words a lot of us have been
working for 10 years to get rid of the
filesystem so the user didn't have to
worry about it when you try to teach
teach somebody how to use aMac the
easiest of allcomputers to use
everything's going along fine until you
hitthe file system and then the
difficulty is staggering for most people
so we've made it on the iOS devices to
where you don'tever have to think about
it the app manages the presentation of
its own documents just like mail manages
the presentation of its own messagesbut
the piece thatwe weren't finished with
was how do wemove those documents
around to different devices and
documents in the cloudsolves that
problem for us apps canstore documents
in iCloudiCloud pushes those documents
toa user's devices automatically the
documents update onall devices when
changed on any device and we are
releasingAPI
so
it's reallyeasy to tie your apps into
iCloud's storage system and again you
canhave complex documents apps like
pagesor we've got another storage
facility for key value dataso as an
example if you've got an app that just
track stocks you can just update the key
value pairsand we'll store that in the
cloudas well so documents and key value
data works across all iOS devicesand
Macs and PCsto
so we think this isgoing to be pretty
bigand that is documents in the cloud
this next one is maybe my favorite one
and it's called Photo Stream and it's
goingto bring the cloud to photos how
many times havewe taken photos on our
iPhone maybe of our kids in the
afternoon andwanted when we got home to
share them on an iPadand have to go
through the process of moving them over
wouldn't it be great if by the time I
gothome they were already there on the
iPad well that's what Photo Stream is
going to dofor us across all of our
devicesso again I take photos on any
device puts it in thecamera roll and
thatwill be automatically uploaded to
the cloud where it's storedand
automatically downloaded to all my other
devices including in this case a Mac and
so I've got my photos onmy iPad just
waiting forme when I get home now in
additionI can import photos right into
iPhoto as anexample on the Mac it'll
upload those to the cloud and do exactly
the samething with them by pushing them
down to all my other devices so it's
apps thatI its photos that I take or
photosthat I import and we built this
right intothe apps I hope you've seen
that as we've gone through this we've
built thisright into the app so there's
nothingnew to learn so photo stream on
the iPads photo app we've built it right
in rightnext to albums we have a button
called Photo Stream you push it and
you're looking at the photo stream it's
that simplethere's not a separate app
that youhave to go learn it's right
there in yourPhotos app it's right
there in your Photos app on youriPhone
it's just right therewith all your
other albums there you goPhoto Stream
on themap on the map we built it right
into iPhotoand so it's right there on
the side your photo stream and on a PC
they don't have aPhotos app so we use
the pictures folder rightin addition to
that we've even built it in to Apple TV
soApple TV Apple TV talks directly over
theinternet directly to the photo
stream servers doesn't even gothrough
your PC talks directlythe photo stream
serversso you can watch the photos
righton your Apple TV so one of the
problems we faced was it will photos are
large andwill use up all the memory on
your devices
there are also large they'll consume
vast amounts ofstorage in our server
farms so we've came up with a great
scheme we're going to store photos on
your deviceswe're going to store the
last thousand photosright let's store
the lastthousand and any photos you
wantto keep permanently just move them
into analbum and they'll stay forever
but they'll be parading by youthe last
thousand photographson your Mac or PC
because we have more storage will store
allof them you can get rid of them by
justdeleting them but we'll store all
of them and on the server will store
themfor 30 days which is more than
enough time for all your devices to
connect and automatically download those
photos sowe think we've got a great
system here that's going to move our
photos aroundamong all of our devices
evenApple TV so that when I take a
photo anywhereI can view it on all my
otherdevices we think this is going to
be really excitingto demonstrate this
I've askedTeddy Q or VP of Internet
services to come on up and giveus a
demoof photo stream
thanks toyou yep so I want to take some
photos to start with now I love cars and
I happen to have brought one of my
favorite ones with me here today and
here it is and we're goingto go to our
my iPhone and launch the camera app
Lightning McQueen is looking good
I love the headlightsand now these
photos are onmy iPhone but let's go
look at my iPad now we've built Photo
Stream right into the Photos app so
rightnext to albums this photo stream
and there is the pictures I just
I didn't have to learn anythingnew at
alland if I want to save them
permanentlyon my iPad I can just select
them and move themto an existing album
or even create a newalbum that's it
now these photos aren'tjust on my iPad
they're on all of my deviceslet's move
over tothe Mac where I've got iPhoto
running and we've built againPhoto
Stream right in and there are the photos
I just took so now when I take a photo
on one of my devices they automatically
appearon all of my devices without
having to do anything at all it's that
simple
and that'sPhoto Stream
that wasgood okay not awesome
so photos you takeor import upload to
iCloud iCloud pushes them to all your
devices works over Wi-Fi its iCloud
storeseach photo for 30 days which is
plentyenough time for all the devices
to be connected devices store the last
thousand photosand again you can just
drag themto an album they stay forever
and Macs and PCs store all photos so
we're really reallypleased with Photo
Stream we think you're going to like it
a lot
last butnot least is iTunes in the
cloud
you know it's the sameold story right
about I buy something on myiPhone right
wolfand and it's not on my other
devices
I grab myipod and I go to listen to
thatsong I bought yesterday on my
iPhone it ain't there well the first
thing we've done again is for the songs
you've already bought we've added a
purchase button that shows you your
entire purchase history of all the
iTunes songs you bought on any device
you can look at it by all songs or
recent songs or you canlook at it by
artist so I'm going to pick Bob Dylan
here and Ican download any of these
albums thatI've bought on iTunes to
thisdevice just by pushing that cloud
download button or I could go in to one
of them and just download whatever songs
I want to this device so anything I
boughtI can now download to any of my
devices at no additional charge which is
great
this is the first time we'veseen this
in the music industryno charge for
multiple downloads two different devices
and for the future I flick one switch to
onand now any song I buy on any device
again will automatically be downloaded
to all my devices so when I want to buy
a songin this case an Adele song it
will push it to all ofmy devices so to
give us a demo ofthat again I'd like to
inviteEddie up thank you thanks Steve
so I'm on myiPhone and I want to listen
to a song I'd previously purchased on
iTunesbut it's not in the music library
on this device well now I can easily
just go to the iTunes Music Store
there's a new purchase tab right on the
bottom and nowI'm seeing all of the
purchases I've ever done oniTunes I can
evenlook at them the songs that I had
thatare not on this device that I
previouslypurchased by just tapping
that buttonnow I'm going to look for a
Foo Fighterssong I think it's called
walk
and there it isand what just tapping
the iCloud button it downloads to my
iPhoneagain because I'd previously
purchasedthis song it's downloading at
no additional costlet's go ahead and
play it
just finishing downloading now that's
great but iTunes in the cloud is even
betterlet's see what happens when I
purchase a new song and if we can bring
up my iPad I'm going to go ahead and
launch our newmusic player in iOS 5 and
on my iPhone I'm going to go back to the
iTunesstore I want to buy a new song
and Iwant to look at the Bruno Mars's
new albumI know he has a hit song I
think it's called lazy lazy song that's
itwe can preview it that's definitely
it now I'm going to buy it but before I
donotice on my iPad I don't have any
Bruno Mars songs at all so we're going
togo and buy and it's now downloading
to my iPhoneand in addition there's the
BrunoMars song
and of course thequail I just wanna
make so now when I buy a song on one of
my devicesit automatically downloads to
all of my deviceswithout having to sync
or do any work atall and that's iTunes
in the cloud
thank you verymuch is this awesome
so musicpurchase from iTunes high
quality 256 kilobits AAC and you can
haveup to 10 devices downloading your
music to all of them everytime you buy
it on any deviceiTunes in the cloud so
these9 apps constitute iCloud and they
are all free we want we wantevery user
totake advantage of these and we know
if we make them free that they'll they
will and we wantpeople to see what
these devices can really do and what the
softwarecan really do so we're making
it free and we're very excited about it
so that's iCloudit stores your content
and wirelessly pushes it to all your
devices and it's integrated with your
appsso everything happens automatically
so a competitor that doesn't own the
appsor doesn't have great developers to
integratewith their apps they can never
do thisthey can never make it so it
just works and that's what we've done
here so how do you get it well when you
upgradeyour phone or buy a new phone
with iOS 5 on itall you have to do is
type inyour Apple ID and password and
that's itand you'll go to switch that's
iCloud you can turn it offif you like
will be turned on by default and you're
up andrunning we're also going to give
everybody fivegigabytes of free storage
for mail documents and backup and that's
even more than it sounds like because
we're not countingpurchase music apps
orbooks towards that five gigabytes
nor arewe counting photostream
towards thatfive gigabytes so when can
you get your hands on this today
we're going to getyou all a developer
betatoday and also today we're going to
make something availableto end-users
which is the iTunes in the cloud portion
and it runs on iOS 4.3 it will run on
allthe supported platforms and when we
ship it this fall but today we'regoing
to put it out for4.3 as a beta and
everyone canget their hands on it and
run it on their existing existing iPhone
4s so wethink this is going to be
really excitingand of course we ship
iCloudconcurrent with shipping iOS 5
this fallso that is iCloud
now there'sone more thing a small thing
it pertains to iTunes in the cloudas
you recall iTunes in the cloud is just
for the music that you've purchased from
theiTunes Store now at 14 billion songs
15 billion excuse me that's a lot of
songs out there
they've been purchased fromiTunes Music
Store but you may have some that you
ripped yourselfand there's three ways
youcan deal with that one
you can syncyour new devices over Wi-Fi
or cable a cable and you only have to
sync them once just toget that music on
them and thenyou can rely on iCloud to
take careof getting all your new
purchases off iTunes onto that device or
if it's just a few songs you love you
don't leave behind you can buy those
songsthat you'll miss on iTunes we're
going tooffer a third way which is
callediTunes Match what is iTunes Match
well iTunes Match uses the fact that
we've got 18 million songs now in the
iTunesMusic Store and the chances are
awfully goodthat we've got the songs in
our storethat you've ripped and so we
wrote softwareto scan those CDs the
ripsi teen on iTunes music and match it
upwith those songs we have in the store
right andso we can give that music the
same benefits as music purchase from
iTunes and it takes just minutes not
weeksif you have to upload your whole
library into someLocker in the sky that
literally takes weeks this takes minutes
because we're scanning and matching your
library sowe don't need to upload that
that largepart of your library and the
few songs thatremain well we'll upload
them but with 18 million songs they're
most likely to have what you've got
in addition iTunes Match will upgrade
those songs that match the 256 kilobits
AAC
and iTunes Match cost just $24.99 a year
so if you'vegot a bunch of music if
you've got a bunchof music that you
didn't buy from iTunes youcan get all
the benefitsof the cloud service and
morein terms of upgrading your music
for $24.99 a year nowif you look and
comparethat to some competitors let's
just look at Appleand Amazon and Google
your kind of get surprised because again
the library in the cloudwe scan and
matchthe other guys you got to upload
your wholemusic library again it's
going to take weeks music apps on your
Macand PC and while you're stuck with a
web app instead of iTunes upgradeto 256
kilobits per second theother guys
aren't upgrading you at all the annual
price for5,000 songs we're $24.99
Amazon charges you $50 for the storage
andGoogle hasn't announced their
pricing yet evenat 20,000 songs we
charge one flat price Amazon's up to
$200 for the storage and Google has an
announcerpresent
most ofour customers won't need this
because they bought a lot of their music
oniTunes but for those that do
it's anindustry-leading offering let's
put itthat way
so that's iTunes Matchand it goes along
with freeiTunes in the cloud
and that's what it isnow
if you don't think we'reserious about
this you're wrong this is our third data
centerthat we just completed it's in
Maidan North Carolina this is what it
looks like
it's rather largeit's as eco-friendly
asyou can make a data center with
moderntechnology and we're pretty proud
ofit just to give you a feel for its
size
see those two littledots on the roof
those are two peopleright there so it's
a pretty large place and and it's a full
of stuff a little expensive stuff okay
and we areready we think for for our
customersto start using iCloud and we
can't wait toget it in their hands so I
cloud is the thirdthing we want to talk
about today I hope you like all the
three thingsthat we've unveiled this
morning and againwe've got a great week
plan for youwith 5200 attendees over
120 sessions over 100 hands-on labs and
over a thousand Appleengineers here all
week so please askus for any help you
needthat's why we're here so go at it
have a great week and thankyou very
much for coming
you