[Music]
there's lots of waysto be as a person
and some people express their deep
appreciation in indifferent ways but
one of the ways that I believe people
express theirappreciation to to the
rest ofhumanity is to make something
wonderfuland put it out there and you
never you never meet the people you
never shake their hands
you never hear their story ortell yours
but somehow in the act ofmaking
something with a great dealof care and
love
something's transmitted there and it's a
wayof expressing to the rest of our
species our deep appreciation so we need
to be trueto who we are and remember
what'sreally important to us that's
what's gonna keep Apple Appleis if we
keep us us
[Music]
thank you
I love hearing his voice and his
inspiring messageand it was only
fitting thatSteve should open his
theater it is the honor of a lifetime to
be the first to welcome you to the Steve
Jobstheater Steve meant so much to me
andso much to all of us there's not a
day that goesby that we don't think
abouthim
memories haveespecially come rushing
back as we prepared for today and this
eventit's taken some time but we can
now reflect on him with joyinstead of
sadness
Steve spirit and timeless philosophy on
life willalways be the DNA of Apple his
greatestgift his greatest expression of
his appreciation for Humanity would not
be asingular product but rather it
would be Apple itself we dedicate this
theater to Stevebecause we loved him
and because heloved days like this
where he could share our latestnew
products andnew ideas of the world and
we do so not onlyto pay tribute to
Stevebut to inspire the next generation
of creators and innovators Steve was a
geniusand one of the many ways that he
showedthat was in the his uncanny
ability
to unlock the talentof everybody that
he worked with he thought deeply about
our workplaceand its surroundings and
he believed thatthey should inspire
talented peopleto do their best work so
over a decade agohe began to work on a
newcampus for Apple his vision for
Applepart was to create an incredible
workplace of the future where engineers
and designerscould all be together
collaborating on the next generations of
Apple productto change the world
Steve's vision and passionlive on here
at Apple Park and everywhere an apple
today and always we honor him
we're here todayto talk about some
incredible products but before we get to
thatI'd like to take a moment to talk
about what's happening in Florida and
Texassoutheastern United States and
across the Caribbean our hearts go out
to allof the people whose lives have
been disrupted by hurricanes
Irma and hurricane Harvey you're in our
thoughts we send you our strength you
are in our prayers Apple is working
closely with relief and recovery efforts
through hand in hand andthe American
Red Crossand in addition to Apple's
direct contributionswe're making it
reallysimple for the entire Apple
community to donate via iTunes and the
App Storethe handed hand benefit for
hurricane reliefairs tonight on all of
the majorbroadcast networks and I
encourage youto watch it and however
you choose to give I hope that you open
your heart tothis important effort
thank you
now let metell you a little bit about
our new home will start moving in Apple
Park later this yearbut of course such
a large move it's really moreof a
process and the first big step is the
openingtoday of the Steve Steve Jobs
theater it's the most state-of-the-art
purpose-builttheater ever built for
events just like this one
Apple Park has been built toreflect
apples values for both technology and
the environment it connects to
connects extraordinarilyadvanced
buildingswith a rolling Park land to
form an open and inspiring environment
for our teams to create and collaborate
the parkitself was converted from a sea
ofasphalt into a hundred and
seventy-five acre green space with over
nine thousand treesApple Park is
designed to be seamless with natureit's
open transparentit brings the outside
in and connectseveryone to the
beautiful California landscape
it's powered by a hundred percent
renewableenergy thank you
and in fact we haveone of the world's
largest on-site solar installations
right here andjust like everything we
makeapple parkas has been designed with
extraordinaryattention to detail
incredible precision and really
beautiful materials we've got a great
visitor center which willbe open later
this year where we will welcomeeveryone
and inside the visitor center you'll
find an incredible augmented reality
experience or you can learn more about
Apple Park its design and its
innovationsyou'll also find a fantastic
new AppleRetail Store as you know Apple
Retail has always been about more than
selling it's about learninginspiring
and connecting with people
now our stores are also the bestplace
to go discover explore and experience
our new products so before we get to
some incredible productswe'd like to
give youan update on retail and to do
thatI'd like to invite Angela Angela
good morning thank you it's greatto be
here and I love the fact thatthe same
team thatdesigns Apple Park also
designs our largest retail stores around
the world but it's funny because we
actuallydon't call them stores anymore
we call them town squaresbecause
they'regathering places for 500 million
people who visit us every year places
where everyone's welcomeand where all
of Apple comes togetherbut what really
brings it all to life is Tim saidare
our incredible teams we've always said
that our people of our soul and they're
Apple's greatest differentiator because
theybring personal connection to
communities all overthe world they
humanizetechnology but along with our
amazing teams our commitment to design
also sets us apart
tomake things simple beautiful and
that's why we thinkof Apple retail as
Apple's largest productsand like all of
our products we've designed new features
to take the customer experience even
further in our largest cities where we
can wecreate a Plaza a space open to
everyone come in and relax meet up with
friends or just listen to a local artist
on the weekends inside we've designed a
foruma place for customers to come and
create collaborate or just connect again
with one another for local entrepreneurs
and app developers we have a quieter
space in the larger stores called a
boardroom
where they can learn morefrom our teams
or again share with each other and the
genius growth a redesigned more relaxed
service service experience now in the
heart ofour largest stores and lastly
The Avenues kind of like shop windows
arounda town square they're carefully
curated
they change seasonallyto always feature
our newest products and services and
this summerto turn on these new
features we've launched today at Apple
our in-store experience designed to
inspire customers to go evenfurther
with their passions
we started with things that areCort
Apple's DNAthings people most use their
devices for and they trust usto teach
them likephotography music gaming and
app development we've creatednew
programslike photo box where customers
can perfect their photography skills
with features like portrait mode and
memories and we do all of this in a
reallyfun social way by taking them out
to the neighborhood to explore with each
otheror Swift playgrounds where the
nextgeneration app developers can begin
to learnthe basics of coding and one of
mypersonal favorites teachers Tuesdays
where ourteams help local educators
stay updated on the newest technologies
and appsin some of our larger stores
sessions are led by local artists like
thismusic lab called the art of beat
makingwith RZA
and the Rowley team in Brooklyn these
sessionsin all stores are led by our
creative team and a new position we call
a creativePro so the creative Pro is
now the liberal artsas the genius has
alwaysbeen to technology and I would
loveto show a quick video to show you
how today at Apple is coming to life
we're learning about photographyyou
have tonsof good ideas in your head so
itwas like oh I like that
I'mgonna explore that some more
when you do somethingfor the first time
you have to be completely fearless
we've just started we've just started
butthe feedback has been fantastic
customers are telling us they love the
role thatApple retail is playing in
their communityso what's next well
we're going to continue to open Apple
town squares in the top cities around
the worldwe're going to invest in
onlineand we're also going to continue
to reinvest in our400 classic locations
includingApple 5th Avenue in New York
Citywhere we're opening up the plaza to
allow natural sunlight to come in into a
greatly expanded space below and you can
see theglass cube will return when
reopen late next year and in Paris we're
restoringan entire historic building on
the iconicseans Alizee we're turning a
five-story atrium into our largest forum
early next yearwe're transforming a
theater beneath Piazza Liberty into a
modern townday Town Square for Milan
just imagine movie night there next
summer
and we'verecently announced an
ambitious project to restore Carnegie
Library in the heart of our nation's
capital we can't think of a better place
for today at Apple programs than a
building originally createdfor the city
to accessknowledge and unlock their
potential and I'm thrilledto personally
announce theopening of our newest
flagship store in the heartof the
MidwestApple Michigan Avenue in Chicago
on October 20th
our team has designeda spectacular
pavilion but seamlessly connects the
plazato the promenade as a part of the
city's planto transform the Chicago
riverfront so that's a brief highlight
justa couple of things we've been
working on and as Tim said Apple's
retail purpose hasalways been to enrich
livesso a huge thank you to the 65,000
apple retail employees around the world
whose passion energy and commitment in
serving allof us every day and ensuring
all of Apple comes togetherit's
brilliant thank you thanks Angela I am
really excited I'm really excited about
all the incrediblethings going on in
retailbut I am especially proud of our
unbelievable retail team it'sthe best
placeto go experience our new products
and so let's get going on telling you
about what we're going to launch today
beginning with Apple watch
Apple watch was designedto help people
stay active motivated and connected so
thatthey could live a better day and
I'mhappy to tell you that more people
are doing that than ever before since
thelaunch of the series - the Apple
watchhas experienced phenomenal growth
in fact last quarter Apple watch grew
over50 percent compared to the previous
year this is incredible
last year we told youthat the Apple
watch had already become the number two
watch in the worldtoday I'm thrilled to
tell you the Apple watch is now the
number one watchin the world
but what's most rewardingto us is how
much our users love it our we have an
industry-leading customer satisfaction
rate of 97%this is whoa why people
writeto us all the time and tell us how
the Apple watchis helping them lead a
healthier lifethese stories are
unbelievableand we prepared a video so
that youcould hear directly from them
what they're telling us I'd love to play
it foryou you did the Apple but again
simpledear Tim Tschida affable hello
mr. cook well I'm piece of keyboard
because that I see I live in
MassachusettsI'm a country boy from
small-town Mississippi I'm a two-time
Olympian
OsheagaMountain Pancho I'm the father
of a nine-year-oldi90 nine year old
every day for thelast two and a half
yearsI have borne this tiny computer on
mywrist this is the first time I've
worna watch since my bar mitzvah I was
a scrawny sportshitting kid who never
really liked being activeI was coming
back froma knee surgery while I was
never fedI was the proud owner of the
dad but I'm feeling to a deep depression
and weighing 250 pounds
what's excuse now I get up at 5:00 yeah
if it'sfive minutes to midnight I'll do
push-ups in my bedroom I'll take the dog
outfor a really quick walk around the
blockI walk around the house and my
familythinks I'm a little crazy
I typically applies whenAtlas reminds
me to stand upevery hour Sybil would
just nosolutions together I ran my
first partner ace in December during a
full America in February
my god or Instagram or post eyes on
nanometers in size
today I've watchedself-abusive gala war
and/or the bum tuition
dear mr.cook our daughter was recently
diagnosedwith type 1 diabetes I called
over three times and my phone landed far
out of my reach
onceI collected my thoughts I
rememberedmy Apple watch had the SOS
future after being rushedto the
emergency roomI was diagnosed with the
condition I was causing my liver kidneys
heartstarts shutting down the
integration of her glucose monitorwith
the Apple watch lets us make sure her
bloodsugars don't go to dangerously low
levelsfor six minutes I hung there in
my car talking to a dispatcher until
help arrived had I notbeen wearing my
Apple watchI never would have sought
medical attentionwhich in turn saved my
life
sincerelyPaul thank you so much for
creating something that does not make me
feel
oh thanks for listening avi sincerely
Stewart ha ha all the best
Tara clearly Oh Jill Casey still got
that with you immediately
thosestories are so movie and there's
really no words todescribe what it
feelslike to receive these knows I'd
like to thank everybody in the video for
sharing their personal experience with
all ofus we have some great news about
the future of Apple watch and to share
itwith you I'd like to invite Jeff fobb
Jeff thanksDan those stories are really
great and it's it's really inspiring to
us that so many peopleare getting
healthier with Apple watchwith watch OS
4 they're gonna be able to do even more
we're addingsmart activity coaching
which isgonna help more people close
more rings more oftena completely
redesigned workout app with high
intensity interval training new features
for swimmers likeAuto sets and gym kick
an industry-firstit's really simple you
just tap your watch on the machine get
goingand all your metrics are in sync
what one of the things that enables
thesefitness features is the apple
heart rate sensorand it's been at the
coreof Apple watch since the very
beginningand today it's the most used
heartrate monitor in the world and we
wantto use it to help even more people
so we're doing three things first we're
making enhancements to the heartrate app
to give you moreinformation now you'll
see yourheart rate right on the watch
face so you cankeep an eye on it with
just a raise of the wrist and when you
launch theheart rate app you'll see new
measurements like resting heart rate
Apple watch calculates this daily by
correlating background heart rate
readings with accelerometer dataand
recovery heart rate which tells you how
quickly your heart rate drops after
workout a lower restingheart rate and a
quicker recovery rate can be signs of
improvedfitness and now you can keep a
better picture of your heart rate you'll
have a better picturethroughout the day
the second thing we weredoing
is inspiredby many of the letters we
receivedfrom customers who notice an
unusually high heart rate when they
wouldn't expect oneso Apple watch has
beenhelpful for them but we realize
mostpeople won't notice so we're adding
a featureand now Apple watch will
notify youwhen it detects an elevated
heartrate you and you don't appear to
be active and thethird thing we're
doing is focused onheart rhythm our
regular heart rhythm hasa familiar
patternbut when your heart beats
irregularly it's called an arrhythmia it
doesn't mean it's beating toofast or
tooslow it just means it's beating out
of its normal rhythm and that can cause
problems the most common form of serious
arrhythmia is called atrialfibrillation
or afiband it affects tens of millions
of peopleand is a leading cause of
stroke but the challenge is many people
withafib don't feel symptoms so it
oftengoes undiagnosed we've been
looking at thisfor a couple of years
and we think Apple watch can help in our
initial studies Apple watch hasbeen
effective at surfacing irregular rhythms
so we're expanding that work and today
we're announcing the Apple heart study
it will use datafrom Apple watch and it
willanalyze arrhythmias including afib
and notify users this study is being
conductedin partnership with Stanford
medicineand we're working closely with
the FDAand they've been great to work
with so later this year the first phase
of theApple heart study will be
availablein the US on the App Store
those are the updates focused on fitness
andhealth and they join the other great
features ofwatch OS 4 we have a
completely redesignedmusic experience
an intelligent Siri face fun new
characters fromToy Story and more so
that's watch OS 4 it will be available
to all Apple watch customers on
September 19
and now I'd liketo introduce the next
generation of Apple watch
[Music]
introducing Applewatch Series three and
it has cellularbuilt-in
now you have the freedomto go anywhere
with just your Apple watch this this has
been our vision fromthe very beginning
and we believe built-in Cellular makes
seriesthree the ultimate expression of
Apple watch now you can go for a run
with just your watch and still be
connectedyou can leave your phone when
you go to the beach or just run a quick
errandand it's really nice to know you
canbe reached if needed while staying
inthe moment you can receive an
important call with just your watch and
and thenumber is the same numbers your
iPhone you don't have to manage a
separate numberthe apps you rely on
like messagesjust work and series at
your beck andcall
anytime anywhere you can use maps and
get directionsand the location for five
my friend automatically switches to your
watch whenyou're away from your phone
and third-party apps like WeChat work
over cellular as well and coming next
month Cellular is going to change the
way we listento music because with
Applewatch series 3 and Apple music you
can stream 40million songs on your
wrist
you'll haveaccess to all your favorite
music you can listen to beats one live
or any Appleradio music station you can
even ask Sirito find you the perfect
tracknow the best device for staying
motive for staying active has all the
music youneed to stay motivated what to
enable thesefeatures on Apple watch we
havepacked Series three with the most
advanced technologies ever in a watch
inside is a new dual-core processor
delivering up to70% more more
performance it's really really fastSiri
is quicker than ever and thanks to the
new processorfor the first time on
Apple watchSiri can talk it's 64
degrees right nowin South Lake Tahoe
it's actually it's really convenient to
not have to look at the screenwhen you
ask it a questionfor Bluetooth and
Wi-Fi connectivitywe developed a custom
wireless chip we callw2 there's nothing
else like it it delivers upto 85%
faster Wi-Fi while being 50% more power
power efficient for both Bluetooth and
Wi-Fiand we've added a barometric
altimeterso now you get flights of
stairs climbed and elevation gains after
a workout we're also releasing an app
for developers thiscan be great for
skiingand snowboarding apps of course
got a snowboarder out there
of course the biggest challenge of all
was adding cellular you see our little
watch isalready packed and you have to
add antennas radios power amplifiers a
SIM cardand if you don't do it right it
gets so big it looks like a house arrest
bracelet and you're not going to want to
wear it so our engineers have been hard
at workand they've come up with some
really creative solutions forexample
rather than add an antenna the display
itselfis the multi frequency antenna
for both LTE andUMTS and of course you
have to havea SIM card but even a nano
SIM would be way too big so instead we
integrated an electronicSIM and it's a
fractionof the size so here's where we
endedup even with all these new
features faster dual-core processor w2
altimeterall the stuff you've got to
put in for cellular the case for series
3 is the same size as series 2
theonly difference is we extended the
back crystalamir 0.25 millimeters
that's as thin as two sheets of paper
it's it's really magical to make a
stand-alone call on a device this small
and I'd like to do that for you
rightnow I'm gonna switch watches so
you guys can see what'sgoing on this
watchis connected over the AT&T
cellular networkthis is our new
Explorer face and I'm goingto tap on
the the phone appand I'm gonna call
Deidre who's a colleague on the watch
team hi hi Deidrehey I'm calling you
fromthe new Steve Jobs theater how are
you doing oh yeah sure sureyou are why
don't we pull in some video and show
everybodywhere you are you know me yeah
that's youdanger give give give well it
looks beautiful out there
well so so far so far so good date a I
should probably cut itoff before
something goes awry but be safe out
thereand thanks for doing this yeah
okay okay that sounds great DJ
come on I'm gonna gorogue for a minute
I you know you got you guys get it but
sometimespeople take technology for
granted and just just for perspective I
might in factI'm actually double mic'd
in just the right location so you can
hear meteachers out in the middle of a
windylake and the only microphone on
Deidre is the little tiny one on the
Apple watchis a foot or two away from
her mouth she's paddling and the signals
beingsent over cellular coming in and
that's just darn close tomagic
seriesthree comes in a wide variety of
casesand bands we have a beautiful new
gold aluminumfinish along with silver
and Space Gray and we're excited to
introducea new band we call the sport
loop it's designed foran active
lifestyleand it's light stretchy and
breathablefor Apple watch Nike plus we
have exclusive new colors and they're
releasing a new version of their Nike
Plusrun club app with great new
features likein run audio coaching and
we have some wonderful colors across all
of our bands that youjust have to see
in personwe have a great partnership
with Hermes and the tradition continues
thisyear with some new watch face
styles some beautiful new bands like the
one on theleft that's inspired by the
classic Hermes driving glove and last
year we introduced a white ceramicwatch
this yearwe're adding a ceramic watch
in a gorgeousgray finish
all of these watches were built with a
great deal ofcare as well as a concern
for theenvironment and they're free of
these harmful materials so that's Apple
watchseries three cellular GPS swim
proves 70% faster dual-core processor
barometric altimeter all the features of
watch OS4 and it still has all day
batterylife up to 18 hours across the
mix of LTE Bluetooth and Wi-Fiwe have
two versionsof series 3 there's one
with cellular at 399and a version
without cellular that has all the other
great features at just 329 and we're
goingto keep series 1 in the line at a
new starting price of249
[Applause]
series 3cellular will be available in
these nine countries with these 14
carriers at launchand six more coming
later in the year and we've worked with
each of these carriers and they're each
off have a special introductory offer
forseries 3 so it's going to be great
and we we are offering the the series 3
withoutcellular in these 26 countries
at launch orders will begin September
15th and availability will be September
22ndthat's the update on Apple watch
and now back to Tim
Apple watchepaulettes is the ultimate
device were healthyin life in the
series 3 takes that to a whole new level
now Jeff showed you some very cool
things you can do with the cellular
function in a series3 and one of those
isto stream 40 million songs right on
your wristwe've made a great ad showing
just that I'd love toplay it for you
[Music]
potassiumwith my hate
this is a big momentfor Apple watch and
we think youare going to love it
next up I'dlike to turn your attention
to Apple TV Apple TV has changed the way
weexperience television simplifying the
way that we discover andenjoy movies TV
shows sportsnews games absence and so
much more
in fact we'vejust been awarded our
second Emmy for Apple TVthank you the
semiwas in recognition for how Siri
makes it soeasy to search discover and
interactwith your TV content we're
really we're really proudof the efforts
we'vemade to improve the TV experience
now throughout the history of TV there's
been a few key inflection pointsthat
have changed the way weexperience
television it of course all began with
black-and-white and it was first
transformed with the introduction of
color it took a hugestep forward with
the advent of HD each stage brought with
it a more true to life experience amore
immersive experience now we're at the
nextmajor inflection point one that has
themost stunning visuals ever that are
idealfor the large TV screens that are
coming into our livingrooms
this will bring cinematicquality to
virtually everythingthat you watch
that's why I am so excitedto introduce
Apple TV 4k
at the heart ofApple TV 4k are two key
technologies that are drivingthis next
evolution of the TVexperience and to
tell you allabout them I'd like to
inviteEddie to the stage Eddie
thank you Tim itis really great to be
here tonight Apple TV 4k is incredible
and it starts with two big advancements
in picture qualityfirst is 4k let me
show you this is an imageand 4k it's
got incredible detail that's possible
because4k has four times the number of
pixelsas HD but resolution isn't
everything there's an even bigger
advancement that's more important and
it's called high dynamicrange or HDR
while 4k is about the number of pixels
HDR is about better pixels let me show
youhere's that same 4k image and here
itis an HDR look at the color the
detailsApple TV can do this because it
supportsthe industry standard HDR 10 as
wellas Dolby vision the best HDR
experience now AppleTV 4k with HDR
delivers the highest picture quality
ever and to show you we've installed a
state-of-the-artDolby 4k HDR cinema
projector in thetheater so let's dim
thelights and let me show you the new
Apple TV and we remasteredour screen
savers our customers love these to take
fulladvantage of 4k HDR
here we are in Dubaiand even at night
you can see incredible details in the
buildings and the carson the road now
here's a city shot that really shows off
the crispness
and sharpness that's possible in the new
Apple TV and we've redone the whole
Apple TV UI in 4k the Texas sharper the
images are brighterand more vibrant but
let's take a look at a 4k HDR clip this
is from the new spider-manmovie coming
to iTunes later this month
yoga's high-tech stuff makes it too easy
hmm sup guys you forgot your PIN number
Wow you're the Avengers what are you
guys doing here
wait be more handsome in person that was
greatand that was all playing on the
newApple TV 4k now at the heart of the
Apple TVwe've got the powerful a 10x
fusion chip this is the same chip that's
in our iPad pro and the new Apple TV
isn'tjust slightly faster it's
remarkably fasterCPU performance is
morethan twice as fast as the current
Apple TV and graphics are more thanfour
times faster and of course it runs the
latestversion of TV OS the best
operating system forthe living room now
to experience 4k with HDRyou also need
great contentand we've been working
with the large Hollywood studios to
bring all of their 4k and HDR movie
titles to iTunesso now you'll have the
biggest releasesin the best picture
qualityall on iTunes all available for
the same priceas HD
and ifyou fought one of those movies in
HD fromiTunes we're gonna automatically
upgrade themto 4k HD are at no
additional chargenow in addition to
iTunes we've been working withleading
streaming providerslike Netflix to
bring their 4k HDR titles to AppleTV
and later this year Amazon Prime video
with all of their 4k HDR titles and
originalsas well now last year we
introduced the AppleTV app an easy way
to watch your favorite movies and TV
showsin a single place it's been
available in the US and today I'm happy
toannounce that we're bringing it to
sevenadditional countries Canada and
Australialater this month and the rest
bythe end of the year now for each
countryit's really important that we
have the content that those customers
know and love andthat's why we're
adding all of these local services to
Apple TVand later this year Apple TV
will doeven more because we're bringing
live sportsso you'll never miss a game
if you're a huge sports fan like I am
you're really gonna love this feature if
yourfavorite team is playing on ESPN
it'll automatically appear rightfirst
in the up nextlist you'll even get
notifications whena games about to
start
or if there's a close game so youcan
start watchinginstantly and if you
scrollup you'll see even more games and
in addition we're bringing live news to
the TV app now let'stake a look at
thosegames as you can see we show you
the scoreand the time remaining to help
you decide which game to watch
and if you're one ofthese people that
doesn'tlike to know the score you can
turn the feature off now we also have a
dedicated sports tab where you can see
every live and upcoming game and as the
seasons changeso will the sports tab
always showing what's you what's best
for youas fort in the TV app is a real
game-changer for sports fans and of
course the new TV app is available on
your iPhone andiPad as well if you own
an iPador iPhone there's no better
choicethan Apple TV you can now share
your photos on the big screen including
live photo effects 4k video memoriesyou
canplay from the over 40 million songs
and Applemusic including the music that
your friends arelistening to and
because Apple TV isalways home you get
anywhere anytimeaccess to all of your
home kit accessories and of course
you've got access to choose from the
thousandsof games and apps on the App
Store and with the 8nx fusion ship
there's so much morethat Apple TV can
do and tosee what's possible we'd love
toshow you a new game from that game
company they're known formaking
artistic and critically acclaimed games
as a matter of fact their first game
called flower was chosen asthe first
videogame ever to be in the permanent
collection in the Smithsonianwhich is
veryvery cool so with that I would love
towelcome their CEO Jenova Chen
at that game companywe treat games as
anart form
today manyof us play games alone but we
believe games is a medium that can bring
peopletogether and that's exactly what
we aregoing to do with our new game
stack together with me as my colleague
Mikeand like why don't we take off sky
is a romanticsocial adventure game well
youfly above the clouds to explore the
wonders ofa mysterious world the game
is designed to be adaptableto the most
casual players the control is simple and
intuitiveeverything can be done with
onefinger on the Siri remote oh hey
that's Mike's friend Jeff and he's
askingus to follow him let's see what
he has discovered compassion and
generosity are key to unveil hidden
areas of the worldas well as growing
your characterso by lighting all the
candles Jeff and Mike was ableto summon
the spirit and he's about to teach Mike
the knowledge of how tosever a magical
creature
in skywe really take advantage of the
powerful new hardware with Matt OH - an
AppleTV's 810 execution chip we were
ableto run the game smoothly even with
these detailed cloudsintelligent
creatures and up toeight players from
anywhere around the worldand let's see
ifwe can draft off one of these
creatures
we don't havetime to show you
everythingso we're gonna skip forward
to the darktemple head light and dark
are important themes of the game in sky
you play as the children of light and
your goal is tobring that light to
where it isneeded the most
where's the lightMike was able to free
all the butterflies and togetherthey
canmove on to the next part of the
adventure with a live orchestral
soundtrack and a cinematic experiences
youcan expect to be immersed in an ever
expanding world so join hands with your
loved ones and play sky exclusively on a
Poe TV I pad and iPhone this winter
thank you thanks Jennifer we can't wait
for you to get your hands on sky we're
soexcited about the new Apple TV 4k
it's got powerful hardware that delivers
stunning4k HDR video live sports along
with live news TV shows and and and
moviesall in the TV app and the perfect
big-screen companion for your iPhone or
iPadthe new Apple TV 4k starts at $179
it joins the existing one you can order
it starting onSeptember 15th and it
shipsjust a week later that is the new
Apple TV 4kthank you and I'd like to
turn it back to ten
I can't wait for you to experience the
beauty and the magic ofthe cinema right
in yourliving room with the Apple TV 4k
next up iPhone
Apple hasalways believed that
technology infused with humanity could
improve people's lives and changethe
world no other device in our lifetimes
have had the impact on the world that
the iPhone has nothingelse has become
so essential or put so much power into
somany people's hands than iPhone it's
trulyamazing how much iPhone impacts
the worldeach and every day our
intention with iPhone has always been
ableto been to create something so
powerfulso immersive and so magical
that the hardware virtually disappears
over thelast 10 years we've reimagined
or invented numerous technologies to
createjust that experience the first
iPhoneforever changed how we interact
with technology by introducing
multi-touch for the first time you were
actuallytouching the software instead
of buttonsit was magical the app store
changed the way wework play learn
communicate spawning new companies and
new industries along the way we took the
viewing experience to places literally
never seenbefore with technologies like
theRetina display we change the way
people communicate with features like
iMessage and FaceTimethat allowed us
all to connect in more meaningful ways
and with Siri we used artificial
intelligence tomake our voices more
powerful iPhone even revolutionized
security and privacy with touch ID and
our walletswith Apple pay and of course
iPhone put amazing easy-to-use cameras
into our hands becoming the mostpopular
way to capture the images of our lives
over the pastdecade we pushed forward
with innovation after innovation after
innovationbringing us to this moment
when now we can create devices that are
far moreintelligent far more capable
far more personalthan ever before
we have huge iPhone news for you today
and it gets started right now
[Applause]
[Music]
iPhone 8 iphone 8 this is a huge step
forward foriPhone and to tell you all
aboutit I'd like to invite Phil to the
stagePhil good morning everyone I am so
excitedto tell you all about the new
iPhone 8 and the new iPhone 8 plus these
are a new generationof iPhone and they
improve on everything we love about
iPhone the design is all new it has
glassin both the front in the back the
aluminum band beautifully matches the
finishof each iPhone a it comes in
silver Space Gray and a beautiful new
gold finish it's made from an aerospace
grade 7000 series custom aluminumalloy
the glass has a seven layer color
processmaking sure there's a beautiful
precisehue and the glass is further
reinforced by an internal laser welded
steel and copperstructure we're so
excited because this glass is the most
durableever in a smartphone iPhone 8
and a plus is also microscopically
sealed for water and dust resistance and
they have a new retina HD display in
each modelthere's a 4.7 inch Retina
display iniphone 8 and a 5.5 inch an
iPhone 8 plus now Apple Retina displays
are renowned fortheir incredible color
accuracyand they have great wide cinema
quality color gamutwe've built in our
3dtouch technology into the display and
for the first time in an iPhone display
it is our true tone technologynow with
true tone it adapts thecolor
temperatureand intensity to the ambient
light around us alongwith the displays
iPhone 8 and 8 plus have new stereo
speakers as wellthey're 25 percent
louder than the speakersat iPhone 7
and they have a deeperbase too and this
is pretty incredible
insideiPhone 8 and 8 plus is a brand
new chip and thisis a breakthrough
performance in a mobiledevice we call
it a11 Bionic this is the most powerful
and smartest chipever in a smartphone
it's a 64-bit design 4.3 billion
transistorssix core we're gonna geek
out here for a bit because itis so
awesomeit has two high-performance
coursethey're 25% faster than the high
performance course and the previous
industry-leading810 chip is for high
efficiency coursethey're up to 70%
faster than the ones in the a-10 chip
they're managed by our second generation
performance controllerthat now can use
all six cores at onceit can deliver up
to 70 percent improvement in
multi-threaded workloads and they have
our first ever Apple design graphics
processing unitor GPU this is a three
core designit's 30% faster than the
graphics in the previous a 10 and the
GPU is designed to accelerate 3d apps
and gamesespecially those that use our
new metal2 framework and the GPU also
is incrediblefor machine learning apps
and those kind of tasksget a big speed
up if they use ourour core machine
learning framework- there's more to it
the 11 Bionic includes our first new
generation image signal processor orISP
so you know this isusing photography
the delivers faster autofocus in
low-light
it has new pixel processingfor
sharpnessand texture and for the first
time to help reduce noise it is Hardware
enabled multiband noise reduction all
this helps to improveperformance and
helps us take better picturesperhaps
the most beloved feature of everynew
generationof iPhone is the cameras and
people lovetaking photos and customers
sent us their photos for our shot on
iphone campaign likethis one this was
sentfrom Jeremy Perez Cruz he shot it
with aniPhone
Plus and people gonnalove taking
pictureswith the iPhone 8 camera it is
an all-new 12 megapixel sensor it's
larger and fasterit provides 83 percent
more lightand it provides more it's
morepower efficient at the same time it
isdeeper pixels and a new color filter
so this adds up tohaving better color
saturationa wider dynamic range of
colorand lower noise in your photos and
videosI phone 8 plus has two new
sensors in its dual camera the
wide-anglecamera has an F 1.8 aperture
and optical image stabilizationthe
telephotocamera has F 2.8 aperture so
as alwayswe want to show you the kind
of photos you can take off of our new
camerasnow these are photos we're going
to show thathave not been retouched in
any way they're straight off the iPhone
8and 8 plus so here's the first one
thisis absolutely beautiful now that's
notthe Golden Gate Bridge this is taken
in Portugal it shows the beauty of wide
color gamutthere's great dynamic range
sharpness and incredibly low noise just
look atthat blue sky here's another
example
it shows incredible Y qualitycolor
again just look at the skin tones and
the detail and the hair in the eyes if
you look closely in her eyesyou can
actually see the photographer reflected
there holdingan iPhone to take the
picture here's a greatexample of the
amazingtextures in depth and
photographyyou can really feel the
fabric and you can see details in their
face behindthe fabric here's a great
example of low-light photography texture
detail and verysubtle colors in this
darker environmentlast year we
introduced portrait mode iPhone8 takes
fantastic portrait modesand people flip
over taking these photos and now with
the iPhone 8 plus you'regonna get
sharper details more uses inlow-light
and even a more natural bokeh in the
background of the photosso this is a
big hitwe had a surprise new feature
last year of portrait mode we brought it
outin beta and it just got better and
better over time and customers send us
photos they love thisso we challenged
the engineering team todo that again to
makeit easy for all of us to take
advantage of an advanced photographic
techniqueand they're doing it and it
hasto do with lighting and if you've
everhad a professional portrait taken
you know thatPro photographers use
advanced equipment and have a great
understanding advanced techniques to
literally sculpt the light on yourface
to create the perfect mood for a
portrait photographwell our team is
makingthis possible for all of us using
the new dual camerasand the a 11 Bionic
chip and the iPhone 8 plusthe team has
come up with a new feature called
portrait lightingthis is beta but it
will ship with the iPhone 8 plus and
here's how it workswhen you compose a
photoin the camera app using the
portrait mode the dual cameras in the
isp sense the scene they create a depth
map they separate the subject from the
backgroundand then you see machine
learning it creates facial landmarks and
actually changes the lightingof the
contours over your face thathappens
while you'recomposing the shot
it's super easyto use right when you're
in the camera app you use portrait mode
and there's a new menu to select the
lighting effect you wantto use you just
swipeto pick a different effect for
whateveryou want to shoot now these
aren't filtersthis is real-time
analysis of the light on your subjects
face in fact you can go in later after
shot a portrait mode photo into the
Photos app and change the lighting
effect to select whichone you want to
useon your photograph
the team has done an unbelievable job on
thisand so here's an example of a photo
that's takennot touched in any way
this is portrait mode using portrait
lightingit's actually using the setting
in portrait lighting for stage light so
it drops awaythe background to make
this stunning dramatic photograph it's
absolutely beautiful
so iPhone 8 and 8 plus are incredible
for taking pictures they're also amazing
for video as wellin fact iPhone 8 has
the highest qualityvideo capture ever
in a smartphone along with the isp we
have an appledesign video encoder this
enables faster frame rates and higher
qualityvideo it does real-time image
and motionanalysis to predict changes
in the contentand optimize the video
encoding algorithms so while you're
shootingvideo let's say for K 60 frames
a secondthe iPhone 8 divides each frame
into individual tilestwo million of
themand we analyze the two million
tiles every second looking for details
like texture and edges to predict
whetherthat tile has grass sky water or
movement init so let's say you're
shooting 4k60 frame rate video you can
look like this it's beautifully
optimized for qualityand for
compressionlevel and this video was
shot on an iPhone in 4k it's amazing and
if you're oneof the many people who
love shooting slow-mo videos that's
gotten a lot better too now you can
shoot a 1080p HD 240 frames a second
that's double the frame rate of previous
absolutely beautiful so nowiPhone 8 is
incrediblefor shooting photos it's
incredible for video there's a third
categoryof use of the camera that's
gonna become increasingly important in
our mobile devices and that's augmented
realitythis is an incredible area for
usto advance in in our teams have
worked together hardware and softwareto
makeiPhone le the first camera the
first iPhone really created for
augmented realityin the first
smartphone designed for it as wellwe
custom tune each iPhone for augmented
reality
the cameras are actuallyindividually
calibrated in the factory andthat makes
a hugedifference in the performance for
AR there are new gyroscopes new
accelerometers anda are kits software
is tightly tuned toall this hardware to
deliver the best experiencefrom motion
tracking an AR greatly benefits in the
newa 11 Bionic chip the CPU handles
world trackingthe new apple GPU renders
amorphous immersive graphics at up to 60
frames a second the new ISP does
real-time lighting estimation andthis
stuff is amazing that it happens on a
device in the palmof our hands so I
want to show you some ofthe work that
developers arestarting to do with AR
apps oniPhone 8 so here's one example
it's a game Warhammer 40k free blade
from pixel toys you can now use their
photo mode to bring the free bladenight
into the real worldand play it right
where your friends arestanding around
you here's anotherfrom Major League
Baseball'sadvanced media team they're
enhancing theat bat app with AR kit so
that when you're at the game you can
holdup your iPhone and see real-time
player information and stats on top of
the game you're watching andhere's sky
guidefrom v STAR Labs you can use AR
kit with this app toactually
superimpose the map ontop of the sky as
you're looking at itaround you this
isn't some generic sky this is the sky
around you
so now we wantto show you a sighting AR
app righthere live on stage playing on
an iPhone8
it's from Directive gamesthis is a new
startup basedin Shanghai it's founded
by developers who haveworked in some of
the biggest franchises in gaming
so please welcomeat Lamarr CEO and
co-founder of Directive games atLee
thank you earlierthe summer with the
introduction of AR kit
Apple changed gaming foreverwhat we're
about to show you is one of the world's
first competitive multiplayer games
designed to be played entirely in
augmentedreality this is the machines
in the game players battle their friends
in real time either online or around the
table in the same roommy friend and
co-founder Andrea is preparing a match
for uswhere we play the rebels against
the dominators
what's reallycool is with a or kit the
metaltwo on the new iPhone we are able
to experience gamesin an entirely new
way these players are able to view the
game from any angle our content has to
be incredibly detailed with the power of
the newiPhone an unreal support for
metal2 we are able to render the entire
level on screen and amazing 1.2 million
polygons while also allowing youto move
in close to really appreciate thehigh
visual fidelity and just look at those
4k texturesit's gorgeous
now shall we go into thegame
AR allows us to use our position in the
real worldto gain a tactical advantage
just look how antha is moving towards
this cave lining up his targets this is
somethingthat would have been hard to
do with tension- it's like you're not
just controlling the game you're in the
game another awesome additionto the
experience is spatial audio if you go
close to the action the sound increases
and if a solidobject gets between you
and the action the sound is occluded
perfectnow with the stereo speakers on
the new iPhone this is truly amazing it
looks like we're gettinghit pretty hard
yes deployshield to protect our heroes
now let's rain fire on our enemies move
closer totheir base and get ready for
thefatal blow with our subbu fe o the
drop ship is there can you take it out
at the sametime
what you just saw is an amazing
evolution in how games areplayed and
experience thanks to the combination of
air kit and metal- on the brand new
iPhone we can't wait for you to play it
look for the machines on the App Store
this month exclusively on iOS
Thank YouAli now let's talk about
Wireless we once said that the future is
Wireless and boy will be right that's
becoming more true than ever beforewith
iPhone 8 it supports LTE advanced for
fast networking connectionsBluetooth
5.0 for thelatest accessories
of course it supportsour great beloved
air pods and the beats X headphones that
use ourw1 chip and the new Beats Studio
threes as well and now with iPhone 8
with its glass back we're enabling the
freedom ofwireless charging I mean this
is a simple thingwe do this every day
we useour phones in the day and we
charge them at night often on a charger
by our bed stand inour homes or in our
hotels and words can't describe justhow
much nicer it is to just put it down and
pick it up whenever you want to charge
withoutever having to plug in a cable
againyou can want to do this by your
bedsideI don't want to do this in a
cafe orrestaurant as they start to
support wireless charging I want to do
it in an airport so youcan top up your
chargebefore you get on the next flight
and perhaps the best use case of all in
your car
youcan get into your car wirelessly
connect and start usingcarplay put your
iPhoneon the center console and it's
chargingall without ever having to plug
in a cableagain what makes this
possibleis we're building into iPhone 8
and 8 plus wireless charging withQi
that she is the leading openness
wireless charging standardand we hope
to help Qi by increasing adoption of it
in creating newuse cases for it many
restaurants shops airports cars have
started to build in support for Qi
wireless chargingand they'll work with
iPhone a many companies are offering qi
chargers and thosethat are chief
certified should allwork with iphone 8
and we'veworked with some developers
whoare creating cheat charges and we're
gonnaoffer them in our stores and
online for our iphone 8 customers
like this one fromthey and this one
from Belkin
so that's iPhone8 it's a new generation
of iPhone
it improves on everything we love about
iPhoneit is packed with innovative
technologies fromthe glass and aluminum
design to the retina HD displays the new
a11 Bionic chip it's there designed for
AR apps like no phone has been before
a new single and dual cameras that
supportfor the brand new photo lighting
effects in portrait mode and wireless
chargingnow iPhone 7 came in these
threeconfigurations starting at 32
gigabytesit will really happen to your
iPhone 8it's gonna start with twice the
capacity at 64 gigabytes and have a
secondone at 256 gigabytes and the
price willbe six hundred and ninety
ninedollars iPhone 8 plus will have the
same two configurations 64 gigabytes and
256 gigabytes and it will be priced
starting at $799 we'll be able to
pre-order them starting this Friday on
September 15thand to be available a
week lateron September 22nd and we can
all upgrade to iOS 11 starting on
September19th so that is iPhone 8 I
like to turnit back to Tim
iPhone 8 a new generation of iPhone and
a huge step forward but we're not
stopping there we do have one more thing
wehave great respect for these words
andwe don't use them lightly our teams
have beenhard at work for years on
something that is importantto all of us
the future of the smartphone the first
iPhone revolutionized a decade of
technology and changed the world in the
process now 10 years later it is only
fitting thatwe are here in this place
on this day to reveal a product that
will set thepath for technology for the
nextdecade
you
[Music]
[Applause]
this isiPhone 10 it is the biggest leap
forward since the original iPhone and to
tell you all aboutit I'd like to invite
Phil back up
Phil thank you Tim I think you can
imaginethere are a lot of people at
Apple that didn't get much sleep last
night preparing for this is this this is
so excitingI mean it is all scream it
is beautiful to look at
it is incredibleto hold the display
fits edge to edge top to bottom it goes
into each corner where it follows the
tight curve of the designit has glass
on boththe front in the back using the
same super-strong formula as iPhone 8
theban is made from a surgical grade
stainless steel that's both durable and
polishes toa beautiful finish and look
how the glass and the stainless steel
fit form a continuous surfacefrom front
to backthere has never been anything
likeit it's engineered to be water and
dust resistant at a microscopic level
comes in twobeautiful finishes space
gray and silver each has an incredible
depthand a pearl essence to the color
in the glassiPhone 10 has an all-new
display
it's called the super Retina display
the love of quality and responsiveness
and efficiency is really quite a
breakthrough in mobile displaysto start
with the super RetinaDisplay is 5.8
inches on the diagonal
it's got 24 36 by1125 resolution that's
over 2.7 million pixels it is 458 pixels
per inch now this is thehighest
resolution and pixel density ever in an
iPhone and it's remarkablehow this
larger display canbe packed on a phone
that fits so comfortably in our hands
the super Retina display uses OLED
technologythis is the first OLED
displaygreat enough to be in an iPhone
traditionalOLED displays have had great
benefits like high contrastand
resolutionand no backlight means it can
make them thinner butthey came with
trade-offsand brightness and rich
colors and color accuracyat least
comparedto our Retina displays but the
superRetina display overcomes all of
thesedeficiencies and lives up to all
that we expect from an iPhone display in
addition the new superRetina display
supports HDR in both the Dolbyvision
and HDR 10 formats it has an incredible
a million to 1 contrast ratio that is
the best color accuracy it integrates
our unique 3d touch technology right
into the displayand like iPhone 8
includes true tone now all this
innovative super Retinadisplay
technology is great but it's thepoint
of it thatmatters and the point of it
is to enable an entirely new experience
that's more fluid moreintuitive so
let's startwith a simplest thing how do
you wake upyour iPhone 10 well
certainly you can raise to wake just
likebefore but now you can also just
tap onthe screen and it wakes up now
with the display going edge to edge and
top to bottom bottom there's no more
home button nowthis is an important
partand a big step forward in the
iPhone user experience somethingwe use
hundreds of times a dayfor so
any tasks is anopportunity to rethink
how iPhone should work and how we can
make it better so now when you want to
go to the home screen you simply swipe
up from thebottom and you go home it's
that simpleit's that easy it's
incredibly smooth and once you do it for
the first timeyou'll know there's never
been a betterway and it works the same
way across the system you're running an
app likemail and you want to go home
what do you do you simply swipe up from
the bottom and you go home it's that
easyand that intuitive it's so much
nicer now the same fluid gesture also
works for multitaskingso if you're in
an app and youwant a multitask you just
swipe upfrom the bottom you pause for
split secondand you're in multitasking
and then you can tap on any app and jump
right toit we also use the home button
for Siri so how are we going to do that
now well of course you can just speak to
your phone as before and say hey Siri
now I didn'tstudy once phones off or
youcan now press the side button in
which has been made larger once you
press it in you canjust talk to Siri I
know what you're thinkingabout well
whatabout unlocking how do you unlock
yourphone with iPhone 10 I mean this
hasbeen very important part of the
iPhone user experiencefrom the very
beginning thefirst iPhone we led the
waywith multi-touch and we created
slide to unlock andthis protected the
iPhone from turningon when you didn't
want it to like in your pocket
starting with iPhone 5s we invented
touch IDmade it fast and easy to
protect allyour data and unlock your
phone with just your fingerprint and
touch ID became the gold standardin
consumer device biometric protection but
we know we can do something that's
better the iPhone 10 your iPhone is
lockeduntil you look at it and it
recognizes you nothing hasever been
simplermore natural and effortless we
call thisface ID
so face ID is the future ofhow we will
unlockour smartphones and protect our
sensitive informationto make face ID
possible it took some ofthe most
advanced technology we haveever created
and much of it is packed right up here
into this tiny little area at the top of
thedisplay we call this the true depth
camera systemand it is made up of
incredible state-of-the-art technology
there's an infrared cameraa flood
illuminatorthe front side camera and a
dot projector and that's not allthere's
also theproximity sensor the ambient
light sensor the speakerand microphone
all packed into this true depth camera
systemarea it is amazing and here's how
it worksevery time you glance at your
iPhone 10 it detects your face with the
flooda new illuminator even in the dark
the IR camera takes an IR image the dot
projector projects out over 30,000
invisible IR dots we use the IRimage in
the dotpattern and we push them through
neuralnetworks to create a mathematical
modelof your face and then we check
that mathematical model against the one
that we've stored thatyou set up
earlier to see if to match and unlock
your phone and this all happens in real
time it all happens invisibly you don't
see these thingsgoing off it's
incredibleit just all works it all
happens to create face IDwe work with
thousands of people around the world and
the teamtook over a billion images and
with that they developed multiple neural
networksto create face ID and to
process the machine learning in face
side these neural networks we built
Apple's first-ever
neural engine yeahthis is a big deal in
our pocketsin our phones is an A 11
Bionic chip with abuilt in neural
engine to process face recognition
now theneuro engine is specialized
Hardware built for a specific set of
machine learningalgorithms this is
another exampleof the incredible
collaboration between the hardware and
software teamsit's only possible at
Applethe neural engine is a
state-of-the-art ultra-fast processing
system it usesour highest density
computing everit's a dual core design
itcan perform over 600 billion
operations per secondand it's used to
thereal-time processing of face ID
recognition but for all of us us it's
just supereasy and fun to use
when you setup face ID you just follow
theon-screen instructions and it tells
youhow to move your head around in the
camera soFez site D can recognize your
faceand that's it you do that once when
youset it up and face ID learns your
faceeven if you change your hairstyle
you decide to put on glasses you're
wearinga hat so you do it up any way
you do itface ID learns your face it
learns who you are and itadapts to you
as your face changesover time let's say
you start to growa beard it works in
day itworks at night and the team's
work hard to make sure the face ID can
easily be spoofedby things like
photographs he even gone and worked with
professional mask makers and makeup
artists in Hollywood to protect against
these attempts to beat face IDthese are
actualmasks used by the engineering
team to train the neural networks to
protect against themand face ID it's
incredible
theteam's worked hard to protect your
face datayes
your facestate is protected with the
secure Enclaveand the AL Evan Bionic
chipall the processing is done on
iPhone 10 and not sent to a server we
require user attentionto unlock that
means if your eyesare closed you're
looking awayit's not going to unlock
nowhow do we compare that to touch ID
how secure is it well there's no perfect
system not even biometric ones but as we
said earlier touch ID is the gold
standard for consumer device biometric
protectionand the data for touch ID has
beenone in 50,000 meaning that the
chance thata random person could use
their fingerprint to unlock youriPhone
hasbeen about 1 in 50,000 and it's been
greatso what are the similar statistics
for face ID one in a million
the chance thata random person in the
populationcould look at your iPhone 10
and unlockit with their face is about
one in a millionand of course the
statistics are lower if that person
shares a close genetic relationship with
youso for example if you happen to have
an evil twinyou really need to protect
your passcodewhere your sensitive data
with a passcode hopefully you don't face
IDalso works with Apple pay so to pay
for things youjust double tap the
button on the sideyou look at iPhone 10
to authenticateand hold it near the
payment terminal to payit's that easy
fast intuitive simple based ID also
works with third party apps third party
appsalready support touch ID and
they'll work with face ID so apps like
mintone password etrade will all work
with face ID so face IDit's faith on
face authentication forunlocking your
iPhone and protecting your sensitive
data they used the innovative to depth
camera systemit's trained with neural
networksit's easy to set up it learns
yourface and it adapts to your face
over time it's aware of your attention
it works with Apple payand it works
with third-party apps this tree def
camera system is incredible
technology and it's goingto enable so
many great new user experiencesthe
first one of courseis face ID but the
teamdecided to create another great
experiencewith it as well this is a fun
one it has to do with emojis that we use
emojis to communicate with others and to
express emotion but of course you can't
customize emojis they only have a
limitedamount of expressiveness to them
so our team created something called an
emojithese are animated emojis
these are emojis thatyou control with
your face in emojis track more than 50
facial muscle movements
they've been meticulously animated to
create amazing expressiveness you just
watch this can you the way youcreate
and share an emojiare right from within
Apple messages you said literally where
are you you canpick from a dozen
different animated emojis to share and
express whatever you want express your
familyand friends so iPhone 10 is
packed withinnovative technologies that
enable new user experiences I'm really
excited to invite out Craig federighi to
show youI phone 10 and one it's like to
use itfor the very first time Greg hey
everybody
Wowwell I'm absolutely thrilled to be
ableto give all of you your first live
look at I phone10 this is a phone we've
beendreaming about for a long time but
the reality of it in your hand it's it's
really something epic so let's take a
look hereis iPhone 10 now unlocking it
is as easy aslooking at it and swiping
up and you know to try thatagain
oh-ho-ho let's uh go to back up here and
get right in so here we are andyou see
this expansive displayit's just a
beautiful canvas for all of your content
and your gestures now I'm just gonna go
intothe weather app here and you can
just see how apps look when they take
advantageof the edge to edge display
now exiting an app couldn't be easier
youjust swipe from the bottom just like
this and throw the app right back on the
home screen let me do that again
just swipe right up let's take a look at
the webit just looks unbelievable
edge toedge on this display and your
photos of course arejust gorgeous as
welllet's jump into this one just
amazing
nowvideo of course is unbelievable on
the super Retina display it looks great
in portrait and in landscapeof course
this is HDR video justincredible
looking now Phil toldyou a little bit
about multitasking on the device let me
show you I'mjust gonna jump into maps
if I want to move between my
applicationsI can just swipe up and
stop my other apps all come inI can get
out ofthem with a tab just lift it's
just that easyand we have a great
shortcutas well you can actually move
back with tween apps just by swiping
along the bottomlike this it's really
easy now you may be wondering about
control center and worry notright where
your status indicatorsare in the upper
right hand corneryou can just swipe
down and get a control centerfrom
anywhere it's that easy
now let's takea look again at face ID
because unlocking your phoneis just
amazingly intuitive you just raise it
look at it and swipe right up to get
started
but now it's also incredibly fastso I'm
just gonna do thatagain I just raise it
look at it
swipe I don't have to wait and it's also
really reallysmart so let's say I wake
my phone and I'mnot looking at it stays
lockedbut once I give it my once I give
it my attention well it unlocksand I
can get rightin it's really cool now
face idea is alsogreat for Apple pay so
I've been atthe register I can just
double click on the side button
I'm authenticated and I can get injust
likethat now the true depth camera
behind face IDisn't just about
authenticationin fact we've extended AR
kit with some incredible new face
trackingcapabilities that provide a
whole new class of augmented reality
experiencesnow we've been working on
one with snapchatand I'd like to show
itto you now so I'm gonna launch in you
see it builds a meshin my face and now
I canjust select a mask the tracking is
just unreal let's check out this onenow
look at the detail over theeyes the
incredible metallic reflectionsthe
qualityof the tracking it's it's just
stunning
now of coursemany of us like to
communicate with emojiand with an emoji
we can now breathe our own personality
into our favourites it's available as an
app right inside a messages I canjust
go rightin here and it immediately
starts tracking me so I can make
whatever expression I want like and just
pick that up and use it as a sticker
drop it on my message like that we also
let you manipulate these infull-screen
you can audition your favorites there's
some reallygreat ones like the kitty
catis so expressive and ferocious it's
a happypuppy check out the physics in
the earsthe pig we've got a chicken and
theunicorn mythical creature favorite
of thestartup
and yes if you were by chance wondering
what humanitywould do when given access
tothe most advanced facial tracking
technology availableyou now have your
answer now these can beso much fun
you'regonna want to share them
unfortunately we let you record messages
I'm gonna record a message here for Tim
heyTim I'm not sure what the protocol
is here but I'd like to call dibs on the
box for my favorite emoji which one do
you like hey Tim I'm not sure what the
protocol ishere but I'd like to call
dibs on thebox for my favorite emoji
which one do you like now you can send
it with just a tap andit appears
there's a looping videoright inside the
transcriptwe're really lucky for our
grandfinale we might just get a
response backfrom Tim oh here it is
let's let'stake a look take me to your
leader
wait a minute Craig I am your leader
let's wrap this thing up
so that is your first look atthe new
iPhone10 and the amazing experience
withthe true depth camera and an emoji
I think you're gonna love it thank you
very much
ThankYou Craig now let's talk about the
amazing cameras iniphone 10 iphone 10
has dual 12 megapixel sensorsdual
cameras both a faster sensors wider
sensorsjust like in iphone 8 as new
color filters new deeper pixelsthere's
an F 1.8 aperture onthe wide-angle
camera and a faster F 2.4 aperture on a
telephoto so that lets in36 percent
more light tothe telephoto camera but
the big newson the camera on the iPhone
10 is it as dual optical image
stabilization that meansthere's OIS
about thewide angle in the telephoto
lens that's a lot of magnets moving
around in a verysmall space but it
helps with compensating forhandshake
and to take better photos and videos in
low-light there's also a better quadled
two-tone flash thatis twice the
uniformity oflight on our subjects so
let's look at somephotos taken from the
backside camera on iPhone 10 this is
absolutely beautifulgreat dynamic range
detail low noise is a beautiful photo
the textures are simply stunning
now there's zero shutter lagand that
helps tofreeze motion so we can get a
photo like this look at that blue sky
with low noise it's absolutely to die
for
the OIS delivers low-light performance
so now you can get incredible low-light
images like this withthe telephoto
camera as wellas the wide-angle an
iPhone 10 is fantastic for the portrait
mode feature that we all love My Phone
10 you get great portrait modes
especially in lower light an iPhone 10
supports thebrand-new portrait lighting
feature as well that's again a photo
taken rightoff of iPhone 10 not
retouched in any way with a stage
lightingeffect dropping out the
background
iPhone 10 is great for photos it's
amazing for 4kvideo and like iPhone 8
it's tuned for a our applications as
factory calibrated cameras the new
gyroscope accelerometerthe performance
advantage of the a 11 Bionic chipsCPU
GPU and ISP and I our kit is tuned for
iPhone 10 now the backside camera that
we use somuch is not the only camera of
courseon the iPhone we have our front
side camera as well and people love to
use those for taking selfie photographs
and now with iPhone10 and it's true
depth camerait really delivers a
breakthroughinto the photos you can
takefor selfies because now with
selfiesyou can take portrait mode
photos as well and it also supports
portrait lighting all through the front
sideto depth camera
and people gonna be blown away butthe
selfish you can take with theiPhone 10
thisis absolutely beautiful of course
everything we've seen is powered and
iPhone 10 by the amazing new a 11 Bionic
chip we talked all about aniPhone 8 but
it's worth hittingon the highlights
again because there has never been
anything likeit a 64-bit 6 core
designed4.3 billion transistors to
high-performance course for
high-efficiency cores our new
second-generation performance controller
that uses allsix cores at once our
first Apple design graphics processing
unitthe brand new ISP that improves
autofocus the video encoded that is
real-time motion analysis while you're
shootingvideo the knurl engine and of
course the secure Enclaveto protect our
face ID dataall this performance I'm
sure as youexpect does come with the
hitto battery life so I think it's
important totell you that we've
increased it yes itlasts
againhardware and software teams work
really hard to deliver two more hours of
all-day batterylife to us so wireless
just likeiPhone 8 iPhone 10 is also
built for a wireless world it is Qi
charging through theglass back and it
willwork with the Qi charging devices
like the onesthat we mentioned earlier
fromMophie and Belkin it also worked
withthird-party two devices that are Qi
certified and there are alot of great
devices they're gonna start to come to
marketparticularly because of iPhone 8
knifeown 10 but we also think we can
make the wireless charging experience
even better so our team wants to create
somethingI think all of us we're gonna
wantto use and it might actually help
move the entireindustry forward so
we're gonna giveyou a sneak peek of
this idea right nowI'm sure many of you
do thisI do this have a lot of Apple
productsI love them and use them all
daylong I charge them at night you plug
in your cables you plug in yourchargers
you take those cables and charges with
you on the roadwhen you travel we think
we have anidea of how to make this a
better experienceand here it is it's a
matthat you place your iPhone 8 or
iPhone 10 down and itjust starts to
chargeand there's a beautiful new
interfaceit doesn't stop there you can
place yourSeries 3 Apple watch down on
itand it starts to charge as well and
youcan place your ear pods or the
optionalnew wireless charging case on
it and it startsto charge as well they
all charge
this system has a great interface the
intelligently worked together and
communicate with eachother to manage
the charging through one more efficient
charging system this isnot possible
withcurrent standards but our team
knows howto do this we call it air
power we hope people love it
that encourages others tocreate more
advanced solutions based on technology
like thiswe're gonna be working with
the chief standards team to incorporate
these benefits intothe future of the
standards tomake wireless charging
better for everyoneso look for the air
power charger next year sothat is
iPhone10 it is the future of the
smartphone it is packed with many
innovative features huge lists we won't
go through them allthey add up to a new
better experience we're soexcited about
iPhone 10we created a beautiful video
to tellyou all about it for more than a
decadeour intention has been to create
an iPhone that is all display a physical
objectthat disappears into the
experience
this isiPhone 10 developing the fulmen
display togetherdefines a whole new
integration making the boundary between
thedevice and the screen hard to
discernthe custom OLED panel was
engineered to fold and seamlessly
combined with the external surfaces
mechanical buttonsgive way to touch in
gestures there's no home button a single
swipe takes you to the home screena
more responsivetouch system means the
gestures in iOS 11 are more fluid the
polished stainlesssteel band reinforces
thewater-resistant all glass design
this newglass formulation their most
durableever in a smartphone enables for
the first time wireless charging our new
true depth camera system contained
within this tiny spaceuses
extraordinary depth sensing technology
to let you unlockyour phone with a
glance
we callthis face ID it Maps the unique
geometry ofyour face with over 30,000
invisible dots this data is analyzedby
the mural engine on the a11 by owning
ship the first of its kind your iPhone
now recognizes you even in the dark and
will adapt to your physical changes this
makes your faceyour secure password so
with justa look
you canauthenticate your phone or use
Apple paythe true depth camera also
enables new experiences like bringing
emojis to lifeby mapping more than 50
facial musclesin real time so you can
be happy or sad or cross both the front
and rear facing cameras now have full
frame mode and forthe first time you
canactually define the light in a scene
based on fundamentals photographic
principles portrayed lighting produces
the effectof real studio lighting on
the backthe dual camera system is
completely redesigned it's made even
smarterby the a11 Bionic chip with
machine learningthe camera detects
elements in the scene to optimize the
imagebefore the photo is even taken the
camera we use every day nelle delivers
so much moreand as iOS becomes the
world's largestplatform for augmented
realityit will redefine what's possible
this isonly Flemington team works hard
to make iphone eight in iphone 10 and
the mostenvironmentally friendly manner
possible
they have arsenic-free display glass
mercury-free displays their BFR free PVC
free beryllium free but now madewith a
low carbon process for their aluminum
designand their highly recyclable with
their materials really proud ofthat
less so I like to say it every time
iPhone 10 alsocomes in two
configurations64 gigs and 256 gigabytes
there we priced from $9.99 in order it
starting on October 27th and begin to
ship on November 3rdso this is the
future the smartphone shipping this year
so thisis our lineup for the holidays
now every yearwe say it's a great liner
forthe holidays and it is but this year
is reallyspecial
it starts with iPhone se iPhone 6s
iphone7 the new generation iPhone 8 and
the futuristic iPhone 10
ten years agowhen Steve introduced the
world to iPhonehe closed with a quote
from Wayne Gretzky it said I skate to
where the puck is going to be not where
it has beenSteve said that's what Apple
doeswe skate to where the puck is going
to be and that is what iPhone 10 is all
aboutthank you doctor you
iPhone 10 this really is the future
we've made agreat fun new ad that I'd
loveto show it to you
[Music]
that is iPhone10
thank you thankyou
oh good
so one morningwe've had Apple watch
seriesthree with cellular which gives
you the freedomto go anywhere you want
with or without your iPhone Apple TV 4k
brings themagic of the cinema straight
to your livingroom with incredible 4k
and HDRcontent iPhone a a beautiful
glass design incredible cameras wireless
charginga 11 Bionic ship and of course
powerful AR capabilities we think you're
going to love it an iPhone 10 the most
advanced iPhone we've ever made the
incredible new design face IDtrue depth
camera systemand more powerful
technologies than we'veever put in an
iPhonebefore it really is the future of
thesmart phone and we began this
morning with some inspiring words from
Steve one of the ways that I believe
people express their appreciation to the
rest of humanityis to make something
wonderful and put it out there we work
really hard at Apple to create wonderful
things and we hope you love what we've
introducedtoday I think Steve would be
really proud of them
I'd like to thank everyone at Apple who
made today possible I'd like everybody
anapple to stand up that are here
representing theirteams from hardware
andsoftware and services please stand
up in operationsare amazing retail
employees
[Applause]
and everyonethat works so hard on this
theater and on Apple Park one ofthe
great things about this theater is an
unbelievable hands-on areait is the
most beautiful hands-on areawe've ever
had by farand I would encourage all of
youto join us there and get your hands
onthese wonderful products thank you so
much for spending the morning with us
thank you
[Applause]
you