now this is why we getso excited when
we're working  on a new version of iOS
because we know that we can positively
affect millions of developers and
hundreds of millions of users and that
isexactly what we've been up  to the
team at Apple has beenworking
incredibly hard  on the latest version of
iOS and today it's a great thrill that I
announce  iOS 7
iOS 7 is the biggest change to iOS since
the introduction of iPhone it's packed
with amazing new features and a stunning
new user interface we prepared a video
to show you our thinking behind the
design and I'd like to run  it for you
now
we have always thoughtof  design as
being so much more than just the way
something looks it's the whole thing the
way something actually works on so many
different levels
ultimately of course design defines so
much of our experience
I think there is a profound and enduring
beauty in simplicity in clarity in
efficiency true simplicity is derived
from so much more than justthe absence
of clutterand  ornamentation it's about
bringing order to complexity
iOS 7 is a clear representation of these
goals it has a whole new structure that
is coherentand it is applied across the
entire system
we'veconsidered  the tiniest details
like refining the typographyto much
largerones  by redesigning all the icons
and developing a grid system allowed us
toachieve a much more harmonious
relationship between individual elements
we've also incorporated a whole new
palette of colors
distinct functional layers help
establish hierarchy and order and the
use of translucency gives you a  sense of
your context these plains  combined with
new approaches to animation and motion
create a sense of depth and vitality
the iPhone responding to your movements
drives the parallax to create a whole
new experience of depth in many ways
we've tried to create an interface that
is unobtrusive and deferential one where
the design recedes and in doing so
actually elevates your content even the
simple actof changing your wallpaper
has a very noticeable effect on the way
your iPhone looks and feels across the
entire system
while ios7 is completely new it was
importantto us to make  it instantly
familiar
we wantedto  take an experience that
people know very well  and actually add
to it to  make it more useful  to make it
moreenjoyable
to createit we brought together a broad
range of expertise from design to
engineering  with what we've been able to
achieve togetherwe see  ios7 as defining
an important new direction and in many
ways  the beginning
you are going to absolutelylove ios7
this thank you this major effort this
major effortis only possible  because of
the incredible collaboration between
Johnny and his amazing design team and
Craig and his incredible engineering
team without further ado I'd like to
invite Craig back up to take you through
iOS 7the biggest change to iOS since
the iPhone
well on behalf of all of the engineers
and designers who worked so hard to make
today a realityI'm absolutely thrilled
to have this opportunity to show you
iOS 7 let's take a look it's
unbelievable it's just gorgeous
from thetypography on this lock screen
to the vitality of the background of an
animation to the home screen with these
icons looks so great it just looked
fantastic
and you know a lot of us have our own
wallpaper you know we like pictures of
our family there and now that liveliness
actually carries through to the  home
screen because as you move the device in
your hand it actually tracks your motion
and as parallax thix but you can see
behind the icons it's really incredible
and it carries over across the  system
this liveliness let me just take a look
at somethinglike  weather where the
motion conveys this information and
where the edge to edge design just takes
advantageof every pixel on that Retina
display it's so nice it's great for apps
youuse  every day like messages your
calendar your email is gorgeous your
friends never look more attractive and
GameCenter  we just completely ran out of
green felt
and would as well this has got to be
good for the environment
the clocks look great and even apps like
stocksand compass  they just have this
look of precision thesense of purpose
the best way to appreciate  iOS 7 is to
see it live I'd like to give you a demo
rightnow so let's take our  first live
look at iOS 7 here it is you can  see how
device actually responds to the motion
in my handjust slide out the lock
screen you see how it  slides in I want
you all to look away for  a moment while
I type in my okay you can lookagain
don't tell anyone about that all right
so here we are on the  gorgeous new home
screen let's go into weather see on
whether it's a little cloudy today I can
actually tap here the degrees get more
informationlike  humidity and rain let's
swipe through some locations clear and
Sydney kind  of hot in Phoenix here in a
Big Thunder Mountain it's looking a
little little rough we've got some some
thunder brewing oh yeah some heavy snow
here inthe  North Pole and a tropical
stormhere in Gilligan's Island I hope
they got off that Island so
and it's more functionalthan ever if
you pinch you get this gorgeous  overview
of all your cities even with the time so
it's a world clock as well let's take a
look at the calendar so clean its swipe
from days today like this turn it into
landscape see your whole week at a
glance at a big week ahead  zoom out
scroll easily through your months even
go all the way  out to the year let's
take a look atmessages you notice  as we
scroll we have this great sort of
playful motion the bubbles let's bring
up the keyboard
you slide contents of the keyboard you
see thelayering  and transparency gives
you that sense of context there's this
gesture now from the left edge of the
device it's great for using  the device
of one hand if I want to just go  back I
can just swipe from the edge of the
displaypull back like that  move in out
so cleanand natural  let's take a look
at foldersthat go here into my games
folder  can have multiple pages store
hundredsRider awesome
take a look at Game Center
some of those good-looking friends let's
take a look atmale the type is just so
cleanand you're drilling  to a message
look at how you get these fullscreen
edge-to-edge  photos it's really great
andthat gesture for  moving in and out
works here too of course just move
between messages just like this so great
and if you just slide across on any  item
you can get  it the trash and more
options as well right here  in mail
finally let's take  a look at
Notification Center same as always we
can just swipe down from the top of
their Vice comes down  with a nice thud
you can see all notifications just my
missed ones and we have this great  new
today view so you can see your friends
birthdays current look at the weather or
up coming in invitations your calendar
your stocksand even a quick look at
tomorrow you know what's really great is
for the first time ever Notification
Center is now available from thelock
screen  as well you don't even have to
unlock your device so that's a quick
look at iOS 7 it's a comprehensive
end-to-end redesign of the user
experience installing iOS 7 on your
phone is like getting an entirely new
phone but when you already know how to
use one that's so much more beautiful
and functional than ever before but iOS
7 is actually more than that it's also a
major feature release as well I have  10
features I want to talk to you about
today starting with control center
control center is something that's so
simple and yet so essential you have
those switches that you just want to get
to really  quickly from wherever you are
well now with control center swipe up
from thebottom of  the device
and there they are
turn onairplane mode  adjust your
brightness play a songeven  get a
flashlightand  available from anywhere
including your lock screen so if you
wake upin the  middle of the night you
need to find something your flashlights
right there and that's control center
next let's talk about multitasking now
iOS 7 has always been built on the
industrial strength foundations of OS 10
and had intrinsic  powerful multitasking
capabilities but we had to be careful
about  how we've exposed these two
applications because we want to preserve
great battery life now in iOS 4 we did
add support for select kinds of
applications to do multitasking things
likeplaying music in the background or
receiving a voice over IP call while
your app was in the background
well now in iOS 7 I'm pleased to
announcethat we're going  to have
multitasking for all apps with great
so how does itwork well imagine  you
have an app thatyou're using  constantly
throughout the day a social networking
app or somethingyou're checking  in all
the time well iOS 7  is notices that
pattern of use and is going to  provide
that app with frequent background
activity to stay up to date let's see if
another app you usemay be that you  just
check-in on in the morning breakfast
maybe at night after  work well iOS  7
notices thattoo and it's going  to give
that app background cycles just in time
so it's up to date for when you need it
now in addition  to this intelligent
scheduling iOS 7 does opportunistic
updates the average user wakes their
device dozens of times a day and  those
provide great opportunitieswhen the
system's already  powered up to update
apps in thebackground  it also adapts
intelligentlyto network conditions  so
if it's a good coverage it's a great
time tofetch and it coalesces updates
across multiple applications so once you
have those radios power it up lets
multiple applications take advantage of
itfor their background updates  and
finally iOS 7 responds to push
notifications as a trigger to give that
application time in the backgroundso
when you follow that notification the
Apple are to be up to date
now Iowaseven  also has a great new user
interfacefor moving  between all the
things you have going on on your phone
now you can double click and  move into
Notification Center and just swipe
between your running applications tap
andmove right  in and that is
multitasking in iOS 7
next let's talk aboutSafari Safari is
the most popular mobile browser in the
worldand an iOS  7 we're making it even
better has a great new full-screen  look
really focus on your content if you pull
down tap at the top you can now get a
smart search field from that search
field you can get it one tap access to
all ofyour  favorites as well as do
searchand access  URLs and it's a great
new interface for your tabs in addition
to all ofthis it has parental  controls
and integration with the same iCloud
keychain you saw earlier with Mavericks
I'd like to give you a demo of  Safari
now let's take a look okay let's head on
into Safari  so here we are in Safari
I'm gonna just zoom in on this page one
you watch as I scrollall the controls
just recede and now you have that full
screen for your content  we've really
improved the way you navigate now in
Safari I'm just gonna tap inhere to a
link to a detailed story we can even
zoom in of course on this page in that
same gesture you saw earlier for going
back well of coursethat works  in Safari
as well so I just swipe in from the edge
of the display and I can navigate back
and forth through my browser history
just  like that it's such a fantastic way
to browse next let's look  at that
unified search field I'm just gonna tap
up hereat the top you see how  I have
one tap access to all my favorites it's
really convenient but I'mgonna type in
this case so I'll type D is and you
notice Ihave a top URL head as well as
Google search suggestions as well
available  all right here we've really
improved bookmarking as well I use this
bookmark control down at the bottom  I
seemy bookmark folders all my bookmarks
we also have shared links you can see
stories posted by people you follow  on
Twitter and my reading list and now just
like you saw in  Mavericks on iOS you can
scroll continue
mostly from article to article without
coming back to the list
it's really awesome next let's take  a
look at tabs and click here at the
bottom intotabs unbelievable  and you're
no longer limited to just eight
and down at the bottom are also all your
iCloud tabs you can see what you left
openon your other devices as well and
tabs they're really nice to use you just
tap sweep intoa tab back out  back in
back out it's just fantastic if you want
to reorderyour tabs just tap and hold
just rearrange them like thisand if
you're done with a tab just swipe it off
to the side and it goes away and that's
the new Safari
let's take a look now at control center
so I'm just gonna swipe up from the
bottom of my display an up comes control
center see have these great switches at
the top can turn on and off Do Not
Disturb  for instance access my
brightness  can even access a flashlight
really useful at night play a  song and
of course this is available to me
everywhere so if I'm in Safari for
instance let's bring it up here you  can
turn off that music and you notice how
it's layering and transparency take the
personalitythe environment where you
bring it up
that's control center
next up multitasking it's just a great
wayto get  across all the things you're
doing on your device so if I just double
click here on  my home button jump into
multitaskingI can just swipe across
everything I have running you want to
move into one messages double tap back
out move into mail back out just like
this it's really really nice that's
multitasking in iOS 7 thank you
so of course there's there's much much
more the iOS  7 including airdrop airdrop
is absolutely theeasiest way to  share
with the people that are right around
you so now when you're in any app that
supports a share sheet  you bring up the
share sheet and your friends that are
all around you just show up right there
you tap onone and they're going  to get
a panel right on their display and they
can accept what it is that you shared
they accept it they're taken right into
the app and you know if you want to
share with multiple people you just tap
tap tapno need  to wander around the
room bumping your phone
now this is system-wide for any app that
supports a share sheet and of course  it
uses peer-to-peer Wi-Fi for maximum
speedand all your transmissions are
securely encrypted becauseit uses  the
latest Wi-Fihardware  it's supported on
the iPhone 5 the fourth-generation iPad
iPad Mini and the fifth-generation iPod
touch and  that is airdrop next let's
talk about the camera  so now your camera
and iOS 7 is 4 cameras in one you can
just swipe  from your video camera to
your photo camera to your square cropped
camera to yourpano camera  and when
you're taking stills you now have access
tolive photo filters from some gorgeous
black and whites  to some classic  color
filters aswell
so with your great new camera we want to
give you a great new way to manage your
photos and it's the new Photos app you
know for many usersthis is what their
photo organization looks like an endless
unorganized stream of their camera roll
we've all been there but youknow it
doesn't haveto be this way there's
greatinformation in those  photos iOS
knows where you took the photos and when
you took them and that provides inherent
structure that we can use to organize
those photos and now in photos in iOS 7
we do we organize them into moments I'd
like to give you a demo of that right
now
so let's take a look now at  the Photos
app so here you see some photos that
weretaken in San Francisco and you see
nothing was done to organize these
photos explicitly and yet they have
these labels like the Palace of Fine
Arts Baker Beach Lombard Street it
provides this natural organization for
appreciating the photos we can go up
there more trips at more time in San
Francisco Golden Gate San Francisco
Fisherman's Wharf but then you see we
have home we have  photos taken at home
and photos taken at the elementary
schooland  around that area and now if
you want to zoomback  out to get a more
of a bird's-eye view  of your collection
we draw these moments intelligently
together into collections so see here
how that multiple day trip around San
Francisco is collected sorry about that
got a little excited there into it's a
very exciting interface into a multi-day
trip in San Francisco andthat time at
home andaround  the school well that's
one moment that's one collection as well
it's a really great way to browse your
photos you can even go all the way out
to theyear level look across  your whole
photo collection
and look at how we pull out the
interesting places that you went in that
year like 2011 was  Colorado and Hawaii
2012 went to South America  you may not
remember when you did itbut iOS does
that's right there and you know with
this Retina displayyou  can even kind of
make outpatterns of photos and when
different occasions are and of course we
found like we had the urge that we
wanted to just tap in right  from here
and so now in fact you can you canjust
tap and scrub and find the photo you're
looking for just like that it's really
just amazing  so I can just pick a photo
here whichever one I want it's kind of
cute and now we can edit it because we
have photofilters so I can go into the
filtershere  I can try different color
effects and if I find one I like maybe a
nice blackand white can do  it just like
that
I'll ply it save that photo away we also
have great new waysto share your  photos
in the photos apps let's bring up
sharing we have a airdrop right here if
any of you were runningiOS 7 I'd see
you it looks like it didn't leak so
that's good you're not in there right
now  but you have airdrop you have  access
to other photos you can share them from
right here
just really handy great photo sharing
option is iCloud photo sharing I'm going
to tap onthat now it's going to iCloud
photo sharing and from here I can select
the photo streams that I want to share -
so I'm on Family Photos  now but I'm
goingto drill in and I can see other
photo streams I've set up and now other
peoplecan share into my photo stream as
well so these are shared photo streams
I'll just select a photo stream here and
type a little message we'll post that
photoso we've  made it really easy  to
share and we've also made it a really
great experience to experience  the
photos you and others have shared with
this new shared tab at the bottom so I'm
going togo in  here see my photo with a
commentI can see the  comments of other
people and the photos that they've
shared and now we even support sharing
video via iCloud photo sharing and we
have a great way to just browse those
shared photos I just tilt the device
into landscape I can scroll through  it
like this and just look at how beautiful
that is
what a great way to experience your
photos so that's the new Photos app in
iOS 7
so integration with Internet services is
a huge part of the experienceof iOS  and
never more so than an iOS 7 so to  take
you through some of those features I'd
liketo  bring up Eddy Cue Eddy
great job Craig thank you thanks it's
greatto be here  so let's talk about
Sirithe first thing is Siri has a
gorgeous new interface now as I speak
you'll see  a sound wave across the
bottom  and you get the results in a
beautiful gorgeous clean way but Siri
has always been a lot about your the
voice of Siriand we've got an all-new
voice hiwhat can I do for you  and you
can also choose a male voice hi Eddie
what can I do for you and we've got high
quality thank you we've also got high
qualityfemale and male voices for
FrenchOh what  these we keep eat as  well
as German  musk honey 32 nettie and we're
gonna be addingother languages over
time now Siri is also getting a lot
smarter  it knows how to control more of
your device
so you could say play my lastvoice mail
or turn on Bluetooth or increase my
brightness
and it can answer a lot more questions
because we've integrated some new
serviceslike Twitter  so you can see
what people are saying or what's
happening we've integrated the world's
largestencyclopedia  in Wikipedia and
we've even integrated web search results
fromBing  right inside of Siri and it's
great forphotos  too and that's some of
the new features of Siri in iOS 7 now
Siri is also a big part of our next
feature iOS in the car now 95%  of the
cars being sold today have integrated
musicplayback and control  from an iOS
device but we want to take this
integration to a whole nother level what
if you could get iOS on the screen that
is  built into your car so that  you can
make phone calls play music go to maps
get yourAI messages  right on the screen
in your car or eyes free using Siri so
now when you make a phone call it's
going  to look something like this call
John Appleseed or play get lucky or go
to maps get directions or even get your
AI messages read to you and you can
dictate a response all eyes free
now all these car manufacturers are
introducing iOSintegration in 2014  and
I know which one I wantto buy and
that's iOS inthe car  next the App Store
now the App Store looks beautiful  it's
way easier to find apps  than ever before
we've added a  new feature where you can
look for apps based on your age range
kids categories parents are goingto
love  this and apps near me you can find
the most popular apps based on your
currentlocation so now let's say I'm at
AT&TPark in  San Francisco and here are
the apps I would see or I'm at the
Louvre in Parisor I'm in  Union Square
shopping it's that easy to discover new
apps it's really great now the next
feature I know you're all going to love
because every day you see something like
this well no more because the App Store
updates your apps automatically
next let's talk about music  the music
app in iOS 7is beyond a doubt  the best
music player we have ever done the first
thing you'll notice is we provide you
with beautiful artist images right in
your library you just tap an artist and
you see the songs but it's not just the
songs on your device you see all of your
purchase music from iCloud right in  your
library and if you want to hear one of
the songs you just tap and you get our
beautiful now playing screen but it's
not just your purchase music in the
video apps you get all of your movies
and TV shows right for my cloud right in
your library it's really really great
turn the  device sideways you see your
albums you can just swipe to see more
and once you seewhen you like  you tap
and zooms right in now the music app is
the best way to listen to your music but
today we're introducing an amazing way
to discover new music and we call it
iTunes  radio
and here's what it looks like it's built
right into the music app but rather than
tell you about it I'd love to show it  to
you and we'll launch the music app and
the first thing you'll notice is we've
got a setof featured stations that our
programming team have createdso you can
see the songs that are trending on
Twitter rightnow  or even the songs that
you guys are all going to hear this week
at WWDC but I feel like summer songs so
you just tap and once you have a station
you love you can just tap the I and you
could share  it with a friend or even
create a new station  based on this
artist or song I can easily skip to the
sea what's the  next song
I'll go back to stations but it's not
just the featured stations that we
provideyou can create  your own stations
here are some  that I've previously
created but I feel like doing something
new now  our music team is providing you
with hundreds of stations based on
alternative country classic rock but I
feel like doing something a little more
specific how about some Led Zeppelin
so it starts off witha great Led
Zeppelinsong let's go ahead  and see
what else is on this station and a great
thing is I can always modify the station
I can just tap the star and I can say
play more songs like this or never play
this song or add it to my wish  list now
I like this so let's play some more
songs like this now another great
feature of iTunes radio is it keeps
track of all the songs that you're
listeningto across all the stations all
your devicesand you can  get to them by
just tapping history you can see them
allhere you can preview and buy right
from there  and that's iTunes radio
so iTunes radiois built into iOS  7 it
works on your iPhone your iPod Touch and
your iPad it's also built into iTunes on
your Mac and PC and evenin  your living
room builtinto Apple TV iTunes  radio is
free with ads and if you're an iTunes
Match subscriber it's completely ad free
we're starting in the US and we'll be
addingother countries over time and
that's the new music app on iOS 7 it  is
the best music player we have ever done
thank you
Thank You Eddie so 10  amazing features
in iOS7 and a  comprehensive end-to-end
UI redesign and of course we're bringing
it all to iPad as well  now there's more
to iOS 7 than we had time  to talk to you
about in depth here today
things like FaceTime audiowhere you now
can doaudio only  high quality audio
calls over Wi-Fi on any iOS device
notification sync so if you dismiss a
notification on one device you don't
have to deal with it over and over  again
on your other devices great feature for
our users in China with integration of
the popular microblogging website site
Tencent Weibo and for those of you who
have peoplewho  just won't let go
phone FaceTime and message blocking also
for our enterprisefee  customers per app
VPNnow there's yeah a couple enterprise
people in the audience alright so in
addition to all this there's one feature
I want to talk about in a little bit
more detail which is activation  lock so
hundreds of millions of us use Find My
iPhone to find our phone when it's just
lost inthe couch or maybe left at
Starbucksbut also when it's been stolen
and now with  activation lock if a thief
tries to turn off Find My iPhoneor if
theyeven wipe the device  entirely they
will not be able to reactivate it
because they don't know your iCloud
username
we think this is going to be a really
powerful  theft deterrent now of course
in addition to being a great release for
our users
iOS 7is also fantastic and major
release forour developers as well the
SDK includes over 1,500 new api's can
add airdrop integrate with third-party
game controllers new api's for  taking
advantage of multitasking ibeacons  for
Bluetooth le micro location sprite kit
for super fast power efficient game
animations and you ident to bring
physics to your UI view animations so I
so iOS 7 isavailable to you developers
in beta on the iPhone today
we'll have betasfor iPad coming up in
the near for the coming weeks and for
everyone elsea final release  coming
this fall so i io s 7 will  be available
foriphone 4 and later ipad 2 and later
the iPad Mini and the fifth-generation
iPod touch that is iOS 7 I hope you love
it